<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataroot xmlns:od="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:officedata" generated="2017-10-13T08:25:55">
<PhoneData>
<ID>487</ID>
<Title>A Light in the East: FREEDOM</Title>
<ArtistName>John Zylstra</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.brittonroadstudios.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>This sculpture was inspired by the freedom movements in the Middle East. The characters on the face spell the word &quot;freedom&quot; in Egyptian hieroglyphs.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZEJmN1JNTExHdTg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420182/-122.66527</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Paul and Teri Graham</Sponsor>
<Materials>Recycled steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Why do you think the artist selected the shape of an obelisk? Can you think of other prominent obelisk-shaped sculpture? (For example, the Washington Monument.) What does the shape of this sculpture remind you of?</Challenge>
<Elements1>We&apos;ve considered the sculpture&apos;s shape. Now let&apos;s examine its scale. To do this, we need to take a look what surrounds the sculpture. How big is the artwork compared to the buildings, trees, shrubs, cars, and people around it?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Hieroglyphic writing was a form of writing used by the ancient Egyptians. The individual characters are called &apos;hieroglyphs&apos;. Notice the stylization of the letterforms. Do you recognize any of the shapes on the front of this sculpture?</Elements2>
<Elements3>This work combines abstract and representational elements. For example, the shape is representative of an obelisk, while the stylized hieroglyphs are abstract. Think about lines and patterns, how do these also explore this contrast?</Elements3>
<Details>The artist references history and current events in his artwork. His work, Tsunami Memorial, was in the 2014-2016 Gallery Without Walls exhibition and referenced the 2011 earthquake, tsunami, and resulting Fukushima Daiichi nuclear disaster in Japan.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture was inspired by the freedom movements in the Middle East and Egypt. What do you know about these events? The characters on the face spell the word “freedom” (phonetically) in Egyptian hieroglyphs. Think about your own freedom. When do you feel the most free? What allows you to be free? Are others as free as you are?</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational and Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational and Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>479</ID>
<Title>Adam Let&apos;s Go For a Bite, Snakes and Apple Column</Title>
<ArtistName>Ed Humpherys</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.wallawallafoundry.com/exhibition/humpherys/</ArtistWeb>
<Description>The serpent is mentioned in Genesis in the Bible. Adam and Eve were enticed by Satan. I have created a modern day enticement for you as Adam or Eve, &quot;Go for a bite!&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRbXp6WHFud1VEaG8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419854/-122.666806</LatLng>
<Sponsor>James and Pam Frank, Metis Wealth Advisory Group</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.jamesdfrank.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Cast bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>The artist also has a piece in the permanent collection called Wormy Apple. You can find this piece in Sundeleaf Plaza. Do you see any similarities between the two works? What about differences?</Challenge>
<Elements1>What is this sculpture made of? How do you think the artist created all those snakes?! Are they all alike, or do they look different? Are they all moving in the same direction? What does this pile of snakes rest on?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Notice the use of line in the piece. How would you describe the lines used here? The artist says he likes to use line to create movement. Where do you see movement in this sculpture? Can you move your body like the lines you see in the artwork?</Elements2>
<Elements3>How many snakes do you think there are here? Can you see all of the apples? How do the repeated forms affect your experience of the piece? What colors has the artist used to create contrast?</Elements3>
<Details>This sculpture references the Bible’s Genesis story about Adam, Eve, the serpent, and the apple. Where did the artist put the apples? Why do you think he put them there? How many apples can you find?
What do you know about this story?</Details>
<Story>The artists references the impact of his religious upbringing on the art he creates. What experiences in your own life have impacted who you are today?</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>54</ID>
<Title>Age of Iron</Title>
<ArtistName>Tom Hardy</ArtistName>
<Description>Ragged slabs of thin plates mounted/bolted to concrete base - 4 each.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBROHVaZVFpc1owdE0</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667277777778,45.4199861111111</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>458</ID>
<Title>Amyas &amp; Soleil</Title>
<ArtistName>Amyas Maestas</ArtistName>
<Description>I am intrigued how artwork can express my feelings, and the way it can inspire people.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNzNrWDBGUlJyems</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420576,-122.664104</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Step It Up Studios and Shirley &amp; Fred Baldwin</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.stepitupballroomsociety.com#http://www.stepitupballroomsociety.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>How old is the artist that created this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - how does the texture of the sculpture differ to emphasize different figurative elements on both Amyas &amp; Soleil?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - the upward movement of both Amyas &amp; Soleil&apos;s arms suggest joy and exuberance.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Contrast - how do the two sculptures differ?</Elements3>
<Details>Amyas Maestas, the artist who created these sculptures, is only 12 years old! He has had artwork on display in other cities such as Grand Junction, Colorado. He is Lake Oswego&apos;s youngest outdoor sculptor to date!</Details>
<Story>Amyas Maestas is Gallery Without Walls’ first youth sculptor to be accepted into the exhibition at the age of 12. This sculpture is a portrait of the artist and his sister.
As an artist and sculptor, Amyas’ goal is to bring a smile to the face of all who view his artwork. His sculpture is designed to be touched and move the viewer. It is meant to engage a lively conversation for everyone. The everyday simple things that surround us are his inspiration– his vision in creating art is to express a view of life that is joyful, playful, and fun.
As a sculptor, the “artist” experience in the public art realm has been very rewarding. Originally sculpted in clay, the finished work of art is cast in bronze. Thus, the art-work is suitable for outdoor presentation. Amyas’ work has had the honor of being chosen Best of Show and given the People’s Choice Award at the Art on the Corner Sculpture Exhibition in Grand Junction, CO.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>361</ID>
<Title>Angkor I</Title>
<ArtistName>Lee Kelly</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.leekellysculpture.net</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTjJyVm9ESEloMEk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66468,45.41775</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What is your initial reaction to Angkor I?  Do you see size, materials or shapes as you first begin looking at the work?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shapes:  Rectangle, square and triangle.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line:  Straight lines move ones eyes from the base to the top and upward.  These lines communicate a sense of the inherent strength of the sculpture.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Balance:  Tripod base, repetition of shapes</Elements3>
<Details>•	Burnishing the steel with a metal sander creates a texture that sparkles in the sunlight.  
•	Note the vertical welded lines in the horizontal central beam.
•	The use of hollow fabricated forms is used to create volume and mass. 
•	This abstract form is framed by the realism of nature’s sky, lake and trees.</Details>
<Story>Lee Kelly’s travels to Nepal and other sites influenced many of his works of the 1980’s and 1990’s.  Lee Kelly has loaned Angkor I to the Arts Council of Lake Oswego and the community for a limited time.  We are fortunate to be able to showcase this nationally and internationally known public artist.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>60</ID>
<Title>Anillos</Title>
<ArtistName>Maria Wickwire</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.mariawickwire.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Ceramic sculpture - Metal</Medium>
<Description>Camel color clay figure of sitting nude with bands of lines surrounding her.  &apos;Mummy-like&apos; figure.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUGVXNXVJMTd4bGs</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.664177777778,45.4191611111111</LatLng>
<Materials>High-fired ceramic clay</Materials>
<Challenge>What do you think the dark lines represent?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture – Course.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Pattern – repeated rings.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line – curved and repeated</Elements3>
<Details>The human form has no straight lines. Coil method of construction, layer upon layer.</Details>
<Story>The artist states, ”The ringed markings on Anillos evokes the annual rings which show the history of an individual tree, including fire, famine, flood, and flourishing.  Like trees, our life experiences are written in the cells of our bodies.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2007&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2007</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>461</ID>
<Title>Anna</Title>
<ArtistName>Julian Voss-Andreae</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://julianvossandreae.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>The human figure reduced to a few hundred triangular planes, welded from stainless steel.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRbTVoU1NvQUFiM0E</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419592,-122.665143</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lake Oswego Vision Clinic</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://lakeoswegoeyes.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How many stainless steel pieces make up Anna?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape - Notice how the use of individual triangles to fabricate this sculpture adds to geometry of the overall form.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Light - The stainless steel lightly textured finish creates reflective patterns throughout the sculpture.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Unity - Notice how the repetition of triangular forms creates an overall visual unity of the sculpture.</Elements3>
<Details>Anna is made up of appoximately 600 stainless steel triangles welded together to form this sculpture.</Details>
<Story>Julian Voss-Andreae is a German sculptor based in Portland, OR. Starting out as a painter, he changed courses and studied physics, mathematics and philosophy at Universities. Voss-Andreae pursued his graduate research in quantam physics. He moved to the US to study schulpture at the Pacific Northwest College of Art from where he graduated in 2004. Voss-Andreae&apos;s work, often inspired by his background in science, has captured the attention of multiple instutiuions in the US and abroad.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>473</ID>
<Title>Arp Arc</Title>
<ArtistName>Don Anderson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>applewoodfarmstudios.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Hope for the world is in the kindness we generate.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0BweBioCa2upaVnh1d0V1T0Jlcnc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418544, -122.667105</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Columbia Bank</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#https://www.columbiabank.com/locations/lake-oswego#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How does the artist imitate natural forms in this sculpture? How does he move away from them?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Is the piece symmetrically or asymmetrically balanced? Is the shape complete? Does it suggest motion/growth/change that hasn’t yet culminated?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Can you stretch your arms to make the same shape as the sculpture?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Look around at the surrounding landscape. Do you notice the shapes in the sculpture repeated anywhere in the natural environment?</Elements3>
<Details>Look at the other sculptures that surround this piece. Pick one to compare and contrast with Arp Arc.</Details>
<Story>The artist has 30+ years experience as pipe welder and also hold a printmaking degree from the University of Kansas. He interested in irregular shapes, like fractals, and in the idea of life as a circle with no end. Do you think these interests inspired the work’s shape? The artist is inspired by nature and natural forms, as well as materials such as stone, iron, and wood.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>440</ID>
<Title>Aspens</Title>
<ArtistName>Reven Marie Swanson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>revenswanson.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;A pleasant walk through the woods under a canopy, flickering &amp; dancing.&quot;
Sponsored by the Lake Oswego Rotary Club</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRbVFsWUhjbW5yc1k</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419065/-122.665348</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lake Oswego Rotary Club</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.lakeoswegorotary.org#http://www.lakeoswegorotary.org#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Mild steel, powder-coat and painted enamel</Materials>
<Challenge>An Aspen Tree is State Tree of which State? (hint: The State has 4 letters in its name.)</Challenge>
<Elements1>Repetition/Rhythm/Patterns - 3 similar forms are repeated to give the effect of a grove of trees or one large tree.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Color - the bright use of color enhances the playful quality of the sculpture and reflects the artist&apos;s extensive knowledge of powder-coating.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - the curved line that makes up the stem gives the piece movement.</Elements3>
<Details>Many of the artist&apos;s artworks are kinetic, meaning they move when interacted with. In this case, Aspens is a wind-powered sculpture.</Details>
<Story>As an artist whose childhood was largely spent in the great outdoors of Colorado, this work is an ode to her memory of connecting with nature. Watching the subtle movement of the kinetic sculpture as the &quot;leaves&quot; catch the wind, the artist invites us into her memory of peering through the woods to discover a colorful canopy.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People&apos;s Choice Winner 2017&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People&apos;s Choice Winner 2017</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>264</ID>
<Title>August Trunk</Title>
<ArtistName>Alisa Formway Roe</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.afroemetalwork.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRaGJ3a2ozXzhiQVk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.719786,45.409992</LatLng>
<Materials>Welded mild steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Is this elephant young or old?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Space - positive and negative.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Shape – size of parts give a sense of strength &amp; power.</Elements2>
<Details>Majestic head, broken tusk, and organic form of ears</Details>
<Story>A trip to Africa motivated the artist to sculpt an elephant who could be in the august season of his life, an august (wise) animal or the object of abuse or all of the above.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2011&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2011</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>225</ID>
<Title>Bearly About</Title>
<ArtistName>Steve Tyree</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.tyreesculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>3 bears - Bronze sculpture 
Mother bear - 50&quot; x 18&quot; x 28&quot;
Baby bear1 - 20&quot; x 14&quot; x 8&quot;
Baby bear2 - 15&quot; x 20&quot; x 14&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZks1SDNpTVdQQnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6671,45.4242333333333</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>What&apos;s going on between the mother bear and her cubs?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Rhythm - Implied movement of the figures moves the viewer&apos;s eye from bear to bear.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - Triangular placement of figures.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - Curvilinear</Elements3>
<Details>Placement of the bears in the grass creates a natural environment for these animals.</Details>
<Story>Children visiting the library fell in love with the bears from the moment they were installed.  A jar for pennies was placed in the library and a collection was begun to buy the bears.  The artist, Steve Tyree, was so touched by this effort on the part of the children of Lake Oswego that he donated the bears to the community.</Story>
<Style>Realistic</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>56</ID>
<Title>Blue Light Tower</Title>
<ArtistName>Joel Cottet</ArtistName>
<Description>Tower is made of several sculptural ceramic pieces anchored together to form a column.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRSGJNcHJ4VGUyTGs</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.742897222222,45.417625</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>3</ID>
<Title>Bread Upon the Water</Title>
<ArtistName>Jerry Joslin</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.joslinstudios.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>This sculpture of three children feeding ducks is a familiar Lake Oswego scene.  It is cast 3/4 the size conceived by the artist.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNmswZ3FfVTNGTUk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667861111111,45.4195972222222</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>How realistic are the figures?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Balance - achieved by triangular placement of the figures.</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Line - the diagonals and curves create gesture, action and movement.</Elements2>
<Details>The positions of human figures with the duck create a story line.</Details>
<Story>This portrayal of a common scene in Lake Oswego of children feeding ducks evokes childhood memories for many of us.</Story>
<Style>Realistic</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>446</ID>
<Title>Breaktime</Title>
<ArtistName>Anthony Teixeira</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.anthonyteixeira.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Anthony uses familiar objects to invoke personal reflection.&quot;

Sponsored by Jeff &amp; Teresa Metke, Metke Remodeling &amp; Luxury Homes</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdzNCTDJ5ZDNfaHc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.399257/-122.733450</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Jeff &amp; Teresa Metke, Metke Remodeling &amp; Luxury Homes</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>remodelerportlandoregon.com#http://remodelerportlandoregon.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Cast aluminum, steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What do you think is the artist&apos;s meaning behind representing a hammer with a broken handle and nails that are bent?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - the hammer is fabricated from cast aluminum; the textured and sanded coating is what makes the aluminum look so much like wood.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line- notice how the lines in the hammer help to create the illusion of wood.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Emphasis - the oversized hammer head focuses the viewer&apos;s eye towards the bottom of the sculpture, and the natural movement upwards towards the tip of the broken handle allows  for overall unity.</Elements3>
<Details>This sculpture is made of steel and cast aluminum coated to look like wood over a series of many coats. The artist&apos;s sculptures often use recognizable objects to encourage the viewer&apos;s familiarity and contemplation with the object.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture is about perseverance. Despite the broken handle of the hammer, the title suggests that the break is only a temporary obstacle to overcome.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>474</ID>
<Title>Celilo</Title>
<ArtistName>Gabe Babcock</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>gabebabcock.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Celilo (se-li-lo) the sound of water upon rocks post 1957</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRM1BPOVVjYjVENTg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.417607,-122.663522</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Dyke Vandenburgh Jewelers</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.vandenburghjewelers.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Cedar, basalt, and wire</Materials>
<Challenge>The artist uses abstraction to communicate the complicated history of the Columbia River. Do you think you have to know the story of The Dalles Dam and Celilo Falls to appreciate the sculpture? What do you think his use of materials symbolizes?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Think about the artist&apos;s use of materials. Consider how the work is balanced between heavy and light, hard and soft, and positive versus negative space.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Abstract art takes a familiar form to distill and transform, often using shape or color. Thank about how the artist has arranged the forms to mimic the submerged falls.</Elements2>
<Elements3>How does this artwork compare with the others in Lower Millennium Plaza?</Elements3>
<Details>Read the artist&apos;s statement and consider the form of his work. What do you notice? You might think about the rocks, which used to be hit constantly with water, now hanging silent. What other visual metaphors does the work engage?</Details>
<Story>Did you know? Celilo Falls was the oldest continually inhabited settlement in North America until Celilo Falls went underwater due to the completion of the Dalles Dam in 1957. It was loud! The name in its native languages meant “The sound of water on rocks”.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>442</ID>
<Title>Clackamas</Title>
<ArtistName>Mike Suri</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.suriiron.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Three plates pressed into a vessel form.&quot;

Sponsored by Johnstone Financial Advisors</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdldUR2FaTVB5Tk0</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418766/-122.66709</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Johnstone Financial Advisors</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.johnstonefinancialadvisors.com#http://www.johnstonefinancialadvisors.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Weathering steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How many individual pieces of steel make up this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Space - three steel plates come together to create both positive and negative space.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - although the sculpture is not symmetrical, the artist plays with balance by extending the oar on one side of the sculpture.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture- because the artist uses weathering steel, the texture will continue to transform through the interaction with natural elements.</Elements3>
<Details>Suri acquired the steel plates while working as a demonstrator at Clackamas County Community College. They are remnants not only of our region&apos;s industry, but also the artist&apos;s life and career.</Details>
<Story>Clackamas is three steel plates gently shaped and nestled together into vessel form.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>349</ID>
<Title>Cloud Totem</Title>
<ArtistName>Riis Burwell</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.riisburwell.com/</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRRTd2dlBETk9YbTA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.666894,45.4184</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>Do you find the exterior or the interior shape more interesting?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line – Curved, vertical lines carry viewer’s eye from bottom to top.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Space – Positive and negative.</Elements2>
<Details>Riis Burwell’s sculpture imparts a sense of energy through juxtaposition of form and line.  He begins with a maquette (model) that he hand fabricates into the larger final sculpture.  Move from facing the sculpture to the side of the sculpture; how does it change?</Details>
<Story>“My sculpture draws its vitality from my reverence for nature and my fascination with the opposing forces of geometry that underlie the structure of the physical world.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2011-2013 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2011-2013 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>141</ID>
<Title>Complement II</Title>
<ArtistName>Merrilee Moore</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.merrileemoore.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>2 pieces:
- Stainless steel free-form sculpture, burnished (62&quot;high x 33&quot; wide x 18&quot; deep)
- Stainless steel cage of colored glass balls (70&quot; high x 33&quot; wide x 18&quot; deep)</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBReEhuNnBPM01uM3M</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.408146/-122.724225</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless steel, glass</Materials>
<Challenge>How are the two parts different?  How are they similar?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color – creates the emotion of joy and gives rhythm &amp; variety to the work.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Space – positive &amp; negative.</Elements2>
<Details>Fabricated Steel.  Each glass ball is hand blown by the artist.</Details>
<Story>Each piece is individually unique and can stand on its own; yet when they are placed together, they create a perfect “complement” to one another.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2008&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2008</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>477</ID>
<Title>Contemplation</Title>
<ArtistName>Ben Dye</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.bendyesculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Public art should be treated as the jewelry of the community, enjoy!</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNUNjZnRLcVZadnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420116/-122.670271</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Kelly and Glenn Heard, in honor of Helen Heard and Jo Ellen Anderson</Sponsor>
<Materials>Stainless steel</Materials>
<Challenge>The artist encourages viewers to explore his work and to interpret it in multiple ways. How many different interpretations can you come up with? Were there different interpretations expressed on your tour today?</Challenge>
<Elements1>What is abstract about this sculpture? What is naturalistic? If this sculpture could talk, what stories would it tell? Consider how both the work’s formal elements (what does it look like?) and its materials impact its story?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Move around the sculpture. How does it change from different viewing points? Which side is the front? How does the recycled steel fit in with the built environment and how does it stand out?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Notice the different textures created in the metal. How many textures can you point to? Does the surface of this sculpture resemble any other material or object?</Elements3>
<Details>The artist has 25+ years in commercial diving experience! Think about the what you’d experience as diver. Does the artist’s familiarity with these materials and this kind of work show in the completed sculpture?</Details>
<Story>Ben Dye&apos;s work is also featured in Lake Oswego&apos;s permanent collection! You can find his sculpture Mutatio elsewhere in the City.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>

<ID>370</ID>
<Title>Crows</Title>
<ArtistName>Tamar Assaf</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.tamarassaf.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Synanthropic species flourish in response to human habitat expansion.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRR2hOaUxrT2VpUTA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6641, 45.420783</LatLng>
<Materials>High-fired Ceramic</Materials>
<Challenge>How do these clay crows imitate real crows in their color, form and location?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Repetition – Placement:  Rhythm and balance move your eyes across the wire.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Form:  Conical</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color:  Blackened birds</Elements3>
<Details>Tamar Assaf has made these birds out of clay on a potter’s wheel.  The shaped form is then shaved with a vegetable peeler, sanded and then fired in a kiln.  The red hot birds are removed and placed in a pile of paper that bursts into flames.  She covers the fire with a pot thereby removing the oxygen and blackening the crows.</Details>
<Story>“Crows are remarkably intelligent. They have learned to utilize the human environment to their benefit – using bread crumbs as fishing bait and dropping nuts into heavy traffic for cars to crush to expose the inner core for their food.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>485</ID>
<Title>East to West</Title>
<ArtistName>CJ Rench</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.cjrdesignstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNXNaWWRWUkZhR1k</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419848/-122.667281</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Chuck and Patt DeRousie</Sponsor>
<Materials>Mild steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What is the first thing you notice when you look at this sculpture? The artist is interested in the role works of art can play in the creation of memories. Does this work stir a specific memory in you?</Challenge>
<Elements1>This work is an example of a monochromatic palette because it uses just one color (in addition to the black base). What sorts of objects are red? What does red make you think of? Why do you think the artist used this color?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Next, let&apos;s consider balance. Is the work symmetrical or asymmetrical? Look at the surrounding environment, what else do you notice that has either symmetry or asymmetry? Be sure to look at objects from both the built and natural environments.</Elements2>
<Elements3>This piece also makes use of positive and negative shapes: the red are the positive shapes and the spaces between are negative. Depending on the time of year you visit this work, what can you see  through the negative shapes?</Elements3>
<Details>The artist enjoys using symbols in his work. What might this be a symbol of? What does it symbolize to you? Trace the lines of the sculpture. How many different types of line do you see?</Details>
<Story>The artist suggests his work inspires joy and visual stimulation, achieved through bright colors and light forms. The artist has a background in industrial engineering and product design. Do you think this experience shows in his sculpture? Where do you notice a balance between light and heavy forms in the work?</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Nonrepresentational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Nonrepresentational</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>467</ID>
<Title>Equilibrium</Title>
<ArtistName>Francisco Salgado</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.franciscosalgado.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Equilibrium: a state of physical balance of geometric forms.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWWthNTBvQndsRHM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419595,-122.667591</LatLng>
<Sponsor>The Vessely Family in honor of Jon C. Vessely, M.D.</Sponsor>
<Materials>Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How many negative spaces do you count within this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - vibrant colors help the sculpture stand out from its surroundings.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - The way the elements are arranged to create a feeling of stability.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Shape/Form - A shape is a self-contained defined area of geometric or organic form. A positive form automatically creates a negative form.</Elements3>
<Details>All three of Salgado&apos;s sculptures that have been a part of Lake Oswego&apos;s Gallery Without Walls have featured the color yellow.</Details>
<Story>Salgado &quot;focuses on creating public art works that  create a sense of place with an aura of playfulness and a nod to  inclusion.&quot;</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>285</ID>
<Title>Fairy Tree</Title>
<ArtistName>John Uppinghouse</ArtistName>
<Description>Structural concrete over a welded steel core.  The concrete is treated with an acryclic filler to make it smooth and slick.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTldJT1ZRX05wb3c</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66112/45.41143</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>460</ID>
<Title>Fat Tire #3</Title>
<ArtistName>Lance Carleton</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.itsallartt.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>I am a contemporary artist creating eclectic sculpture.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRekdmbDdRMlBBekU</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419505,-122.664456</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lakeside Bicycles in loving memory of Carol &amp; Dr. Seymour Haber, the Pastry Fairies</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>lakeside-bikes.com#http://lakeside-bikes.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Steel, copper, ceramics</Materials>
<Challenge>What is the most famous bike race in the world?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Space - The stylized and overexaggerated form of the bicycle allows for a large contrast of positive and negative space.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - How do the exaggerated lines add to the whimsical character of the artwork?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Balance - Despite it&apos;s large size, the sculpture retains complete balance.</Elements3>
<Details>The presence of Fat Tire in the Lake Oswego community reflects that its commitment to a green environment through eco-friendly conveyances. *Interaction with sculptures is at your own risk.</Details>
<Story>&quot;The fat tire series brings a smaile to everyone from age three to ninety-three. Almost everyone can visualize a moment or period in their present or past where this 2 wheel conveyance has provided pleasure and joy in their life.&quot; - Lance Carleton</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>59</ID>
<Title>First Footsteps</Title>
<ArtistName>Jim Demetro</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jimdemetro.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Life size piece of Mom holding baby&apos;s hands while baby is taking its first steps.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQTI0QWJhdTVGUUE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667730555556,45.4199138888889</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Bank of America</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#https://www.bankofamerica.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Cast Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>Why do you think the mother and child are smiling?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Texture - see it in the skin, clothing and hair</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Line - the slanted lines of the bodies allow the viewer to understand what is occurring.</Elements2>
<Details>Patina - observe the color variation.  Face - note the expressive emotion of the mother and child.</Details>
<Story>Portrays happiness at the thrilling moment of a child’s first steps.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realistic&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2004&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2004</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>63</ID>
<Title>Fish Banners</Title>
<ArtistName>Thomas Augustine</ArtistName>
<Description>Three fish banners mounted on street lights.  Auto paint on metal.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNGRzUk5oR3A4d2c</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66239,45.4211</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>480</ID>
<Title>Foot Prints</Title>
<ArtistName>Junko Iijima</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>junkoi.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>I explore the cultural identities of objects and how they relate to our visual memories.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRRUdTMHd4ZnZxQ1E</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418569/-122.667105</LatLng>
<Materials>Cast iron</Materials>
<Challenge>Why do you think the artist chose to sculpt only footprints? Can you imagine what the rest of the body looks like?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Let&apos;s consider scale. How big is the figure that made these footprints? Try sketching the body that belongs to these prints. What shapes do you see? How big are the strides these foot prints are making?</Elements1>
<Elements2>What pattern do the footprints make on the earth? Where are they heading? Try moving in the same direction as the foot prints - where are you going?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Think about the material. What other objects can you think of that are made of cast iron? Do you think this sculpture is heavy or light? Is there an odd or even number of prints?</Elements3>
<Details>Look at the surface of the foot print sculptures. What do you observe about the textures of the surface? Why do you think the sculpture is placed here? Where else could these foot prints go?</Details>
<Story>The artist states that she likes to &quot;explore the cultural identities of objects and how they relate to our visual memories.&quot; Think about this quote in the context of the artist&apos;s Japanese American heritae and the meaning generated through cultural symbols. What icons of your culture can you think of?</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>4</ID>
<Title>Fortuna</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Fountain - armless woman with basket on head.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZ2NDVllmUEN5SVE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.664516666667,45.41805</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze, basalt, iron</Materials>
<Challenge>Find recognizable objects in the rock pile from which the figure, Fortuna, arises.</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line – vertical lines move the eye upward.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Contrast – between the circular basket &amp; rectangular body.</Elements2>
<Details>The water basket on the head of the figure is based on ancient Mayan sculptures.  Her body is patterned after ancient Greek and Roman sculptures that today no longer have their arms.</Details>
<Story>The artist was inspired by Fortuna, the Roman goddess of fortune and good luck.  She rises from a midden (ancient dumpsite) filled with debris.</Story>
<Style>Representational</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>469</ID>
<Title>Genesis</Title>
<ArtistName>Sharon Warman Agnor</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.sharonagnor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Glass</Medium>
<Description>Genesis links ancient creation stories and the human compulsion to make.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBReDRwQUhIQ3hlcTA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419518,-122.666579</LatLng>
<Sponsor>KeyBank</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.key.com#http://www.key.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel, kilncast glass</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you name any of the other artworks the artist, Sharon Warman Agnor, has had in the Gallery Without Walls collection prior to Genesis?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - Notice how the vertical lines move your eye upwards towards the &quot;eye&quot; of the sculpture.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Color - How many colors are included in the &quot;eye&quot; of the sculpture?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture - There are mutliple textures working together to create this sculpture: the smooth stainless steel, the glossy glass, and the textured sparkle glass.</Elements3>
<Details>The artist was inspired by the creation story (the book of Genesis) in the Bible.</Details>
<Story>&quot;Where does the ability to create come from? It seems to be within our human DNA to be makers, solvers, creators. This sculpture is my personal exploration into the origins of creativity and art itself. In &quot;Genesis&quot; there is a cosmic theme, linking ancient creation stories to the human compulsion to create. Here, steel, bronze and glass join with light, darkness, color and the cosmos to probe this marvelous human question.&quot; - Sharon Warman Agnor</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016 - 2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016 - 2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>58</ID>
<Title>Going for Your Vision</Title>
<ArtistName>Alisa Looney</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.alisalooney.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Standing figure in red with extended arms.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRYi1XNEVhVEI2SFk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.661361111111,45.4238333333333</LatLng>
<Materials>Powder coated steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Try to find a straight line.</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - Overall red color brings focus to the sculpture as a whole.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - Diagonal and curvilinear.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Pattern - Cut-out spirals</Elements3>
<Details>Spiral designs symbolize the energy of the body, muscle structure and freedom of movement.  The viewers&apos; eyes move with the sculpture.  Rather than breaking up the piece, the spiral pattern unifies it.</Details>
<Story>In Alisa Looney&apos;s words, the sculpture represents the determination, energy and action it takes to go after your life&apos;s dream.  The color red reflects the fire in your belly when you are moved into action toward your greatest vision.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2006&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2006</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>2</ID>
<Title>Guardian</Title>
<ArtistName>Ted Shillock</ArtistName>
<Description>- Titled abstract figure created from three different blocks of white marble on dark gray-black stone.
- &apos;Guardian&apos; is a follow-up piece to a smaller &apos;Guardian of the Horizon&apos;.  It was created from three different blocks of marble, each with different colored veins.  The pieces are held together with epoxy and stainless steel pins.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRLUJpdVpIUWt2WUE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667180555556,45.4239555555556</LatLng>
<Materials>Italian Marble</Materials>
<Challenge>Is this sculpture like a human figure?  What is it wearing?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape – Triangles, squares and rectangles.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture – Seen, but not felt, in the smooth marble.</Elements2>
<Details>The slanted lines of the sculpture suggest a moving figure that appears to be ready to step off its pedestal.</Details>
<Story>This artwork is appropriately placed in front of the library because as Ted Shillock has noted, this figure represents a guardian or protector of knowledge, feelings and ideas.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>396</ID>
<Title>Guardian of the Lake</Title>
<ArtistName>Brian Mock</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.brianmock.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>aluminum - aluminum</Medium>
<Description>&quot;crafted from 100% recycled aluminum&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWkNhN3NVZ1FmWlk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.395853,-122.68849</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lake Oswego Rotary</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.lakeoswegorotary.org/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Recycled aluminum</Materials>
<Challenge>How many different items can you identify?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Texture - Smooth or rough?</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Shape - Different shaped pieces create an overall texture for the viewer’s eye.</Elements2>
<Details>The idea for a sculpture begins with Brian’s structural visualization that allows him to see a three dimensional image in his mind.  He first draws his idea, then makes a two dimensional form.  Then he chooses from his ongoing collection of scrap metal the exact pieces that he believes indicate the anatomy of the dog.  He welds all pieces to the form and finally smooths all of the sharp edges.</Details>
<Story>Brian Mock explains:  “I am intrigued by the challenge of creating an entirely unique piece of art from a random collection of discarded and often commonplace objects, giving these old, ordinary items a new and extraordinary life.”  He wants the viewers to question the reality of what they are seeing.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>476</ID>
<Title>Guermo en Inverno</Title>
<ArtistName>Jamie Burnes</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jamieburnes.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Cor-ten steel - locust wood</Medium>
<Description>My work focuses on archetypal creatures and forms to express the spirit of life on earth and our interdependence on it.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRX1E5VnZaSzdDa00</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419826/-122.669699</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Don Nussmeier</Sponsor>
<Materials>Cor-Ten steel and Locust wood</Materials>
<Challenge>What opposites or opposing forces do you see in the piece? Think about the juxtaposition of: steel vs. wood, natural vs. human made, longevity vs. decay, abstraction vs. representation, positive vs. negative space.</Challenge>
<Elements1>Where do you notice different textures in the sculpture? What about positive or negative shapes? How would the animal move if it could? Where would it be heading?</Elements1>
<Elements2>The artist has studios in both New Mexico and Massachusetts. Do you think working in these contrasting landscapes impacts the artist’s artwork?</Elements2>
<Elements3>How would this sculpture change if it was all wood? What if it was all steel? It also has both naturalistic and abstract elements. Can you find examples of this contrast?</Elements3>
<Details>The artist likes to combine natural elements (like the earth) with human-made forms (like steel). He is interested in creating archetypal creatures. What does the bull represent to you? What are the characteristics of a bull?</Details>
<Story>Look at the lines of the artwork. How do these create energy? The artist likes to showcase a variety of forms and textures in his work. Where do you notice these various elements?</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>470</ID>
<Title>Fossil 2</Title>
<ArtistName>Lin McJunkin</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.mcjunkinglass.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Glass - Metal</Medium>
<Description>Cast glass cells in steel honeycomb suggests bee&apos;s problems worldwide</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTkRnSWE2MzZ0dW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419433,-122.665665</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Beth Schulberg with Cruise &amp; Travel Specialists</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#https://cruztrav.com/about-us/beth-schulberg-owner/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Glass, Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What are the positive benefits honeybees provide?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Value/light - Notice the contrasting values in the individual glass pieces. Some colors are lighter and more translucent than others, suggesting the honey has become &quot;unpure.&quot;</Elements1>
<Elements2>Repetition/Rhythm/Pattern - The repetition of the hexagonal pattern creates the honeycomb.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color - How does color signify the purity of the honey?</Elements3>
<Details>Honeybees worldwide are suffering from a variety of problems that may be related to climate change, including being out of synch with flower maturation. Pesticide use is also an identified cause of Colony Collapse Disorder. This piece warns of those dangers while reminding us in an attractive way of the importance of bees and their honey for our food supply. The powder-coated metal “hive” is filled with fused glass “honey” of varying colors to represent loss of purity.</Details>
<Story>2 years ago, Washington glass artist Lin McJunkin and metal sculptor Milo White began collaborating to transform sheets of steel and glass into a unique hybrid of sculptural elements. White often begins their process with a metal framework that McJunkin fills with fused or cast glass.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016 - 2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016 - 2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>282</ID>
<Title>In the Flow</Title>
<ArtistName>Stuart Jacobson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.stuartjacobsonsculptor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Shorter basalt column</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRckMwOER4RjZ5Umc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.400816/-122.657179</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>178</ID>
<Title>In The Flow</Title>
<ArtistName>Stuart Jacobson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.stuartjacobsonsculptor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Taller Basalt column</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRckMwOER4RjZ5Umc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.657055555556,45.4004138888889</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>478</ID>
<Title>Joli</Title>
<ArtistName>Steve Farris</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>aestheticsteel.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>I am inspired by classic works from ancient and modern craftsman.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBReHF2RTZBc3hwdkk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418380/-122.666939</LatLng>
<Materials>Rusted steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Look around that this sculpture&apos;s setting. What do you notice about its surroundings? How does this work blend, or not, with its environment?</Challenge>
<Elements1>How many lines do you see? What direction are they going? Look closely at the pieces of steel -- are they evenly or unevenly spaced? How do you think this sculpture was made? What tools might have been involved?</Elements1>
<Elements2>How would you describe the texture of this piece? Why do you think the artist chose rusted steel, as opposed to a highly polished steel,  or a powder-coated steel?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Consider scale. Sometimes artists take an ordinary object and make it extraordinary by aggrandizing its scale. What does this object resemble? What do you think you put in it? Where would it go in your home?</Elements3>
<Details>The artist likes to group these sculptures in sets. Use your sketchbook to draw one or two more pieces to add to the collection! What shapes and sizes did you draw?</Details>
<Story>The artist is inspired by both ancient and modern artworks. What about this sculpture reminds you of a Classical object, and what about it is contemporary?</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>6</ID>
<Title>Leaf Figure</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRMXdPSV96WjNJcW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66356,45.4178</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>55</ID>
<Title>Lotus Tower</Title>
<ArtistName>Joel Cottet</ArtistName>
<Description>Lotus Tower is made of several sculptural ceramic pieces anchored together to form a column 14.5 feet high and 5 feet across, and weighing 1500 pounds.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRMlRDQnQ0UmRxTms</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.396473/-122.651274</LatLng>
<Materials>Clay</Materials>
<Challenge>Think about each piece of this sculpture being made individually by the artist. How many pieces are stacked to create this tower?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Pattern - find references to the lotus flower.</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Shape - cylindrical and symmetrical</Elements2>
<Details>Glaze:  Blue-green color gives a light and airy feeling to this very tall ceramic work.
Unity: Provided by repeated references to the lotus flower petals and its leaves.</Details>
<Story>The lotus flower is an object of perfect beauty in Chinese mythology. Joel Cottet specialized in large-scale pieces he formed on a potter’s wheel. Lotus Tower was originally a part of Gallery Without Walls in 2002/03 and was purchased by the city of LO from the estate of the artist in 2005 after his death.</Story>
<Style>Representational</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>459</ID>
<Title>Mushroom Drums</Title>
<ArtistName>Yelena Roslaya</ArtistName>
<Description>My coil-built sculptures, inspired by udu drums, are abstractly representing soundwaves, which are often heard and not seen. These drums create low and deep sounds, coming from the shape of the hollow clay form as the resonation bounces against the walls of the clay body. Hands are the best when it comes to interacting with this sculptural instrument.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRa0NyWm1QUW9QdUk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420261,-122.664161</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Kids of Lake Oswego</Sponsor>
<Materials>Ceramic, glaze</Materials>
<Challenge>Which drum makes the loudest noise when &quot;playing&quot; it? Hint: Drum on the holes.</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape - The bulbous shapes of the drums suggest an organic form as illuminated in the title, Mushroom Drums.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Color - The contrasting glazes give singularity to each particular drum.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture - the mixed use of ceramic and glaze, sometimes used unevenly on the surface, helps to add texture to the drums, and provides a variety of surface finishes.</Elements3>
<Details>These drums create low and deep sounds, coming from the shape of the hollow clay form as the resonation bounces against the walls of the clay body. Hands are the best when it comes to interacting with this sculpture instrument. Make sure to drum on the holes on each scultpure, not on the sold surfaces of the drums.</Details>
<Story>&quot;Udu drums, which originate in Nigeria, can be found in many varying shapes and sizes. They are used as pots for storing food, transporting water, and as instruments for ceremonial purposes. These drums do not need skin to make their sound and most of them are completely made out of earthenware clay. Yelena’s coil-built drums tend to be organically shaped, in such forms as gourds, mushrooms, and carnivorous plants. The mushroom-shaped drum has a cap form, which is hollow and creates a resonating sound quality when tapped or touched. Depending on its size, the mush-room cap has a hole or two that produce the deepest sound when drummed upon. The stem of the mushroom-shaped drum gradually curves from the cap into the stem, where it’s thicker to support the weight of the sculpture. This thickness of the mushroom drum allows it to withstand environmental wear-and-tear as well as the drumming interaction.&quot;</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>393</ID>
<Title>Mutatio</Title>
<ArtistName>Ben Dye</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.bendyesculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Stainless steel &amp; basalt - steel plate</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Technology and math play a critical part of each sculpture, it is meant to challenge the mind and the eye.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRby1mRnN1WHVSa3c</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.410131/-122.72014</LatLng>
<Materials>Basalt and stainless steel</Materials>
<Challenge>When you move the rods, how does this change your experience with the art?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Line - Combination of straight and curved, repeated</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Movement - Viewer interacts with the sculpture</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Texture - Cut, ground and honed basalt; smooth rods</Elements3>
<Details>“Mutatio” is the Latin word for change, meaning to move or shift.  It is the viewer who changes the sculpture to create a new profile for the next viewer to enjoy and change.</Details>
<Story>Ben Dye started with a 6000-pound basalt column.  He built a diamond wire saw that he used to cut a ten-inch wide slab from the basalt.  The saw does most of the work; it polishes and created texture as it cut.  He then used a template to drill holes for the rods made of stainless pipe that are held in place by stainless steel bearings.  The completed work weighs 1750 pounds.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>484</ID>
<Title>Observation Tower</Title>
<ArtistName>Dale Reiger</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>dalereiger.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>I&apos;m experimenting with light, color, form, and design.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRd01CTlZ6Sk9tTFU</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.42073,-122.665187</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Bonnie Cartwright</Sponsor>
<Materials>Iridized and dichroic glass</Materials>
<Challenge>The artist has talked about a plan to build a true scale building with glass like this! Imagine: What would this building be like inside? What would the light be like? Would it be bright or dim? What about the colors? What might the building be used for?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Let&apos;s look at shape vs. form. Shapes are flat &amp; can be geometric (like squares &amp; circles); or organic (like free-form or natural shapes). Forms are 3D shapes that express length, width &amp; depth (like a box). How has the artist combined both shape &amp; form?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Walk around the sculpture and peer inside. What does the thick iridized glass reveal? What does it obscure?  Iridized glass is coated with a fine metallic coating before the glass is cooled. This coating gives the glass a mother of pearl effect.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Is this a large sculpture or a small building? Consider the role light plays in this sculpture. Reiger experiments with different degrees of luminosity from one side of the sculpture to the other.</Elements3>
<Details>The artist uses color expressively, including iridized (see below) &amp; dichroic glass. Dichroic glass displays two different colors, depending on the lighting. It is produced  by stacking layers of glass &amp; micro-layers of metals or oxides.</Details>
<Story>The artist employs contrast in his work: the bright luminosity of glass vs. dark transparent colors, which allows the light to penetrate, but not  reveal. The artist has a background in painting -- do you see this experience in his sculptural work? Where has he used a more gestural line? Where is he more exact?</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>444</ID>
<Title>Origami #3 - Totem</Title>
<ArtistName>Ken Hall</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.solsticestudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Origami welcomes you to the Evergreen Neighborhood.&quot;

Purchased by the Evergreen Neighborhood Association</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTEg0T21paUxZSWs</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420181,-122.675833</LatLng>
<Materials>Folded and welded mild steel with powder-coat and natural patina finish</Materials>
<Challenge>How many origami folds does it take to create one flower on this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Value - the density of the blue powder-coat enhances the sculpture&apos;s presence on the street and allows it to stand out against its surroundings.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - the verticality of all of the lines in the sculpture encourages the viewer to continue looking upwards.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Space - the distance between each flower is derived from the Fibonacci sequence.</Elements3>
<Details>The distance between each flower on Origami #3 - Totem is calculated through the Fibonacci sequence. This is nature&apos;s numbering system and the sequence appears in natural phenomena such as the arrangement of plants and patterns in flowers.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture is part of the artist&apos;s series of origami flower sculptures. It is based on Hall&apos;s interest in the Japanese tradition of paper folding as well as his observation of Native American totems which can be found in the Puget Sound area where he is from.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>Permanent Collection</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>465</ID>
<Title>Pilot (Stars Aligned)</Title>
<ArtistName>Vicki Lynn Wilson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://vickilynnwilson.net</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Mixed Media</Medium>
<Description>A spiritual exploration of learning, growth and flight.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQnZvbnNpWkdud00</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.41997,-122.668076</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Toniya Villalobos in honor of my mother, Iva Znobia</Sponsor>
<Materials>Steel, cement, enamel paint</Materials>
<Challenge>Point out as many recognizeable shapes and images in the upper half (steel) portion of the sculpture. What do you see?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Balance - Notice how the elements are arranged to create a feeling of stability.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Contrast - Notice the juxtaposition of the white, polished cement with the textured and painted steel to help engage the viewer and add to the complexity to the sculpture.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture - Notice the diverse textures within this sculpture. The steel parts themselves contain multiple treatments and textures.</Elements3>
<Details>Pilot is from a series called &quot;ERA,&quot; made as a way of celebrating the artist&apos;s 40th birthday, as a rite of passage to recognize who she has become.</Details>
<Story>&quot;The human form has such a narrative capacity, and material holds a symbolic language. Here, the figure is a support, a vehicle, and a culture on which to grow my material experiments. In creating this wrok, I release the past and realize my potential. This has been an era of study which I began as an apprentice and ended as a professor. Much of the work I produced in the twenty years preceding was thoroughly planned from the inception. In this work, in the spirit of letting go, I responded spontaneously to the materials and the forms in each stage of completion.&quot; - Vicki Lynn Wilson</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>39</ID>
<Title>Pinecone Bollards</Title>
<ArtistName>Valerie Otani</ArtistName>
<Description>- Small bronze pine cones on 36&quot; tall poles located in a space next to road.
- The bollards depict the legend that the shape of the pine cones of the Douglas Fir are the
tails of mice, running for shelter from the Oregon rain.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUWdaUXdIOEdrQW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.655019,45.407539</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>483</ID>
<Title>Pouffe</Title>
<ArtistName>Hilary Pfeifer</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>hilarypfeifer.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>An exploration of patterns found in nature and culture.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRa0ZzU2EwUGExVlU</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419896/-122.662981</LatLng>
<Sponsor>John and Diane Economaki</Sponsor>
<Materials>Stained cedar</Materials>
<Challenge>Look at this sculpture from a distance. What do you see? Now look at it close up. Describe something new you&apos;ve notice. Run your hand along one of the &apos;pouffes&apos; -- what does it feel like?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Describe the patterns you see on the surface of the sculpture. What do you think they represent? How do you think the artist made these designs? If you were to add another &apos;pouffe&apos; to the piece, what design would it have? What is its significance?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Look at the setting of this sculpture, as well as its materials. Do you think this work resembles either the built or natural environments? Thinking about naturalism vs. abstraction, what about the sculpture is natural? What is abstract?</Elements2>
<Elements3>The artist says this work is meant to resemble Moroccan seating cushions. Think about it, if you sat on them, would they be soft or firm? Would they stay up? How has she carved the cushions? Think about the shapes and lines the artist has used.</Elements3>
<Details>Pfeifer’s public art practice developed out of her experience creating smaller site-specific installations. In 2014 she carved two large wood sculptures for TriMet using cedar trees from the site. These can be seen along the Portland-Milwaukie Max Line.</Details>
<Story>Did you know? The wood used in this sculpture is from a 75-year-old Atlas cedar! Pfeifer grew up in the Willamette Valley and was inspired by the simple cabin her family built near the Oregon Coast. The artist recalls the found materials she and her family used to build functional spaces for them to live. The experience of reimagining space and materials informs Hilary&apos;s artistic practice today.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>133</ID>
<Title>Rams Head Benches</Title>
<ArtistName>Ken Patecky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.patecky.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>1 of 2 pieces.
Two wooden benches with two wooden concrete ram heads, one at each end of the bench.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUzQ0blBySVo0WHM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.717619444444,45.4123694444444</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>464</ID>
<Title>Sail</Title>
<ArtistName>Rodger Squirrell</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://metalsquirrell.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Aluminum/stainless steel welded with explosive bonded weldment.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUUw1aE9FNkxBaW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420327,-122.666776</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Eric J Weberg with Edward Jones</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#https://www.edwardjones.com/financial-advisor/index.html?CIRN=409554#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel, aluminum</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you tell what parts of the sail are made from stainless steel and what pieces are made from aluminum?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line -  The gestural curved and straight lines come together to represent the sail form.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Form - A form is a self contained defined area of geometric or organic form. A positive form automatically creates a negative form. Can you point out the positive and negative forms in this sculpture?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Contrast - How does the texture of the sculpture differ from shape to shape?</Elements3>
<Details>Squirrell&apos;s metal sculptures feature a wide range of industrial remnants and sheet goods repurposed as bold, modern forms. He gives cast off materials new life through the mediums of masks, fountains, wall sculptures, and public art installations.</Details>
<Story>&quot;The material drives the idea, so I accumulate scrap materials that sit around the studio in piles. I usually have three or four sculptures going all the time. Eventually they start to work on me and I have to do something with them. Some pieces don’t gel right away and I just let them sit until they do. I’m recycling more than just the physical weight of the metal. I looked at automobile bumpers for a long, long time before I could see something in them. Chrome bumpers are obsolete now, but a lot of design and tooling, and physical energy is still present. I want to capture that energy – not just put it in a scrap bin and melt it away.
It’s showing respect for the process and the people that made the original part. That’s how I feel about all materials. They represent a lot of work already and I’m trying to add something new.&quot; - Rodger Squirrell
Sometimes the life you give a sculpture is not the life you intended. You’re working in a kind of unknown realm. You have to work slowly and hope that something great emerges. You can only predict things to a certain level. That’s the whole mystery. You can start out to make a horse, make a bad horse, and end up making a good dog.&quot; - Rodger Squirrell</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>482</ID>
<Title>Salmon Romance</Title>
<ArtistName>Pat McVay</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>mcvaysculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>This sculpture is all about the fact that only one almon in a thousand will survive to repeat this incredible cycle.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQUZuUGpKYXE0Rm8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.417653/-122.663772</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Jackie MacGregor</Sponsor>
<Materials>Salvaged red cedar</Materials>
<Challenge>Think about the salmon&apos;s journey from the sea to freshwater. What sort of obstacles and predators must the salmon overcome?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Do you read this sculpture from top to bottom, or from bottom to top? Does your interpretation of piece differ depending if you start with the salmon at the top versus the salmon at the base?</Elements1>
<Elements2>McVay uses two different carving techniques in this sculpture. The base uses relief sculpture, notice that the skeletal fish are attached to the support. The fish, in contrast, is sculpted fully in the round.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Take a look at the different textures McVay achieves on the surface. How would you describe them? Which parts of the wood are smooth? Which have a rough texture? What patterns can you find on the surface?</Elements3>
<Details>Compare this work to Celilo, which is also located in Lower Millennium Plaza, diagonal from Salmon Romance. How do these two artists use similar materials &amp; engage in similar subjects, but do so in different ways? Consider McVay&apos;s naturalistic, lifelike carving vs. Babcock&apos;s abstraction. What do the works have in common? How are they different?</Details>
<Story>McVay is a founding member of the Northwest Stone Sculptors Association and the Cascade Wood Sculptors Guild. He began his career in Paris repairing furniture! After moving to the Olympic Peninsula, his attraction to the natural forms of the forest led him into wood carving. Currently, most of his work is large-scale carvings from already-downed trees, using everything from a chain saw to fine chisels. His whimsical and even comical sense is often the basis of unique carvings of people and animals.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational and Naturalistic&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational and Naturalistic</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>261</ID>
<Title>Spirit of the Marsh</Title>
<ArtistName>Mark Andrew</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.markandrewstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Stone</Medium>
<Description>50 foot long, multi media sculpture graces one end of the Headlee Walkway in Lake Oswego .  Forty-four tons of rock anchor 29 cast bronze cattails in a naturescape which integrates natural with man-made landscape elements.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWGlGU0FLUTlvd1E</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66383,45.41756</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>214</ID>
<Title>Sprout</Title>
<ArtistName>Mike Suri</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.suriiron.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdnRFeGp5blgyNUU</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6645,45.4173944444444</LatLng>
<Materials>Steel with clear coated paint</Materials>
<Challenge>How would Sprout change if it was raining? Cloudy? Sunny?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color – gives the piece focus.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line – creates balance &amp; rhythm.</Elements2>
<Details>Sand blasted metal.  Water &amp; copper sulfate bring out the reddish coppery oxide we call rust.  Solution is washed off to stop the rusting.  Leaves are sprayed with shades of yellow &amp; orange paint.</Details>
<Story>The artist states, “trees, especially during the fall season, inspire a great sense of awe and thoughtful calm”.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2010&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2010</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>70</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;At First&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>6 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>57</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;Dreams&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>1 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  Unpolished on 5 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.657013888889,45.4211888888889</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>67</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;Oregon is Green&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>3 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 5 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>69</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;Perfect Stone&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>5 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>71</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;River with One Bank&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>7 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>66</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;The River&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>2 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>72</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;The Stream&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>8 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford. - 1 unpolished side of 5 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>68</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;You Reading This&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>4 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>462</ID>
<Title>Stone Bench</Title>
<ArtistName>Lloyd Whannell</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.fineartbuilders.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Function and aesthetics joined together, blending into something more.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRX2REWV9meDF6cHc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419743,-122.666506</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Benoit &amp; Associates</Sponsor>
<Materials>Stone</Materials>
<Challenge>What type of stone is used for the actual bench?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - Notice the texture of the top of the bench: smooth and polished; now move your hand under the bench, and you&apos;ll notice the rough, unpolished stone.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - Even amidst the curvature of the bench, the artist is able to achieve balance with the bench and a feeling of overall unity within the piece.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color - Notice how the green of the stone changes value in certain areas. It is lighter in some parts and darker in others.</Elements3>
<Details>The artist uses serpentine stone (green) for the bench part of the sculpture.</Details>
<Story>The bench is an example of the functional work the artist fabricates, combining function with the ability of the piece to hold its own as an artistic sculpture.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realism&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realism</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>47</ID>
<Title>Sunbathers</Title>
<ArtistName>Ken Patecky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.patecky.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>- A mother holds a child on her lap while looking up into the sky.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRMmtJSElfT095bWM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.666213888889,45.4194833333333</LatLng>
<Materials>Concrete</Materials>
<Challenge>We easily recognize this as a mother and child, but what parts of the figures are not realistic?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Line - horizontal and vertical lines emphasize the closeness of the figures and the body positions.</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Texture smooth.</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Color - This monochromatic sculpture focuses the viewer’s eye on the figures.</Elements3>
<Details>The artist first makes a wooden form, then pours tinted concrete into it.  While the concrete is setting up, he sculpts it with a large flat spatula.</Details>
<Story>Legs are extended and faces are raised as the mother and child bask in the sun’s rays.  This timeless and universal portrayal won the 1st People’s Choice Award in 2001.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2001&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2001</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>402</ID>
<Title>Sunflower</Title>
<ArtistName>Patricia Vader</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.patriciavader.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Stainless steel &amp; Aluminum - Stainless steel</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Like the circles that you find in the windmills of your mind&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTTM0T2Etd0VwMzg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.663772, 45.416919</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Dyke Vandenburgh Jewelers</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>http://www.vandenburghjewelers.com#http://www.vandenburghjewelers.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel, aluminum</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you name another artist famous for sunflowers?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Color - Hues of the sun</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Line - Curved stem and petals</Elements2>
<Details>This kinetic sculpture consists of eight windmills. These windmills are made out of bicycle wheels with canted disks, which represent the heart and seven petals of the flower.  The windmills spin in different directions (clockwise and counterclockwise) depending on the direction of the wind and the orientation of the disks. The heart of the flower has road reflectors mounted on each disk that flare up at night.</Details>
<Story>Born in Amsterdam, Vader earned her PhD in Mathematics and Natural Sciences from the University of Amsterdam. She taught Astronomy at Yale University and was an astronomer at the Space Science Telescope Institute in Maryland before moving west and focusing on art, earning an MFA in California.  “My research and creativity focus on technically challenging projects that use the free energy of wind and sun.  I make art that is fun and exciting and filled with motion and light.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>383</ID>
<Title>Sunrise in the City</Title>
<ArtistName>Jesse Swickard</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jesseswickard.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Built to see the sun within the city&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWlJ0Ui1iNXdQb2s</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.407498,-122.675423</LatLng>
<Materials>Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Why is this titled Sunrise in the City?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Form – Contrast between circular and linear</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line – Predominately diagonal</Elements2>
<Details>Jesse Swickard’s training as a metal fabricator and car restorer has influenced his public sculptures.</Details>
<Story>Jesse expresses himself in a visual language.  By using repetitive, rhythmic lines he shows us how he sees the sun rise.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>218</ID>
<Title>Swoop II</Title>
<ArtistName>Devin Laurence Field</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.devinlaurencefield.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Stainless Steel</Medium>
<Description>Stainless steel sculpture.  Terns and other migratory birds swoop and play in the sky over the lake.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRSE9GRnFSdFBRbFE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.664641666667,45.4130111111111</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>466</ID>
<Title>Taos Patriarch</Title>
<ArtistName>Huberto Maestas</ArtistName>
<Description>The best art in the world has a human spirit behind it. It is created from the soul.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdHVTLVhBQnladkk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419611,-122.667778</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Nicoletta&apos;s Table &amp; Marketplace and Shari Newman - Cascade Sotheby&apos;s International Realty</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.nicolettastable.com#http://www.nicolettastable.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>What part of this sculpture looks most realistic?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - Notice how the pronounced lines make this sculpture look more realistic.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture - Is the bronze smooth or rough? Does the texture change in certain areas?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Emphasis - What parts of the Taos Patriarch does the artist emphasize the most? Why do you think he chose to highlight specific parts of the figure?</Elements3>
<Details>The Taos Patriarch represents the Native American elder who used to stand along the portals around the Taos Plaza in New Mexico.</Details>
<Story>Huberto Maestas is a well-known sculptor from San Luis, Colorado. He is best known for religious sculpture and his Stations of the Cross near his home. The Vatican also has a work of Maestas&apos; sculpture in its collection. &quot;As an artist, my artwork is a reflection of the human spirit.  It is in these intangible events that my art takes an intimate look at the moment; the strength of perseverance, power, struggle and dignity in sculptural form. It is in the tradition of the great sculptors of the Rennaisance, that I am drawn to create works of art that inspire our life experiences. The best art in the world has a human spirit behind it, there is a humanity and spirituality that exists in all artwork, whether religious or not, it is created from the soul.&quot; - Huberto Maestas</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realism&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realism</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>463</ID>
<Title>Tempest</Title>
<ArtistName>James Ellingboe</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jamesellingboe.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Form through the repetition and manipulation of a simple shape.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRLXA0UjdwaVhCcE0</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.42008,-122.666522</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Arts Council of Lake Oswego</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.artscouncillo.org#http://www.artscouncillo.org#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>COR-ten steel with weathered patina</Materials>
<Challenge>Who wrote the famous play, The Tempest?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Repetition, rhythm, pattern -  The repeated triangle shapes are welded together to produce a patterned form.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture - Because of the weathered patina on the COR-ten metal, the texture seems rougher. It will continue to transform with the outdoor elements.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - Notice the combination of vertical and horizontal lines keep your eye moving around the piece.</Elements3>
<Details>Because of the COR-ten material with a weathered patina, the surface of the sculpture will continue to transform with the outdoor elements.</Details>
<Story>Ellingboe is an emerging artist, trained as a landscape architect. His sculptural works are often abstract manifestations inspired by math, science and his life experience with the natural world.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>52</ID>
<Title>The Awe and Wonder</Title>
<ArtistName>Lonnie Feather</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.lonniefeather.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>18 window panes are glass of yellow, purple, red, gold, and black pieces including artistic shapes of white flowing lines, green and blue ribbons (river like), brown flower spheres, and white dots in artwork.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRc3k3U0NFaEdCRVk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.663877777778,45.41835</LatLng>
<Materials>Glass</Materials>
<Challenge>Are you looking down into the water or up into the galaxy?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color – subtle hues of purple, green, blue.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Pattern – Grid of the panes creates a balance to the fluid design of the glass pieces.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - Curvilinear</Elements3>
<Details>Three sets of three glass panels with organic shapes ask the viewer to examine their individual framed panes.</Details>
<Story>According to Lonnie Feather, the title focuses on the idea of “the essence of our relationship to the universe – the awe and wonder of life.”  
Note:  You can find The Awe and Wonder by standing in the driveway to the parking structure of Lake View Village and looking above the entrance/exit.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>486</ID>
<Title>The Big Maybe</Title>
<ArtistName>Stashu Smaka</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>stashusmaka.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Yes and No.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRREVxSzNJQUpTQ28</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418388, -122.665881</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Buckley Law P.C.</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.buckley-law.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Cor-Ten steel</Materials>
<Challenge>This piece of art is also a word puzzle! Walk all the way around the sculpture and look for the letterforms the artist has linked together to form this intertwining statement. How many letters can you find? How are they connected?</Challenge>
<Elements1>What types of lines make up this sculpture? Are they stiff and rigid, or curving and rounded? Take a look at the work&apos;s surface texture? The material, Cor-Ten steel, is a weathering steel, which forms a rust-like appearance when exposed to the elements.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Can you move like this sculpture? How is rhythm connected to movement? Would this be a fast moving or slow moving sculpture? Try twisting your body into a letterform. For an extra challenge, can you connect your letter to a partners?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Finally, let&apos;s consider balance. Look at the sculpture from all sides. What do you notice about how the balance shifts as you move around? Think about which letters seem heaviest and which seem light.</Elements3>
<Details>Why do you think the artist elected to NOT add color? What is the effect of the monochromatic palette? Would it look different with color? Which letters would you paint and why?</Details>
<Story>The artist likes to play with language and text and is an experienced metalworker with expert craftsmanship. His work also has a playful and engaging energy; try sketching a phrase, or even your own initials, intertwining them like the artist did in his work.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>157</ID>
<Title>The Flight of Icarus (Icarus Falling)
(Torso)</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRV01idnhCNTFNbmM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6638222,45.4179306</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>5</ID>
<Title>The Goal</Title>
<ArtistName>Lee Hunt</ArtistName>
<Description>3 pieces - one little boy, one young girl, one young boy and one soccer ball in cast bronze.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRMTNXcllOb1RfMGM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.725802777778,45.4248583333333</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>481</ID>
<Title>The Healing Hand</Title>
<ArtistName>Tom Jackson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>Art2Work1.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>steel - copper, brass, bronze</Medium>
<Description>The Healing Hand is reaching out to you.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWXhCM2ZDV3A2M0U</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419701/-122.668128</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Bill and Barbara Warner</Sponsor>
<Materials>Steel, copper, brass, bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>Try comparing the individual small hands to whole huge hand. Think about how the small parts all work together to create a whole. What do you think this might symbolize?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Think about the artist&apos;s use of symbols. Where do you notice symbols on the sculpture? Why do you think the artist chose the symbols he did? What meaning do you think these symbols have?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Consider the combination of naturalism and abstraction used here. The shape of the fingernails, for example, is a naturalistic detail, while their silver color is abstract. Where else do you notice the use of naturalism and abstraction?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Some of the earliest art features handprints (prehistoric cave painting, for example). Why do you think handprints are so iconic? What do they symbolize? Think about the other places you notice handprints.</Elements3>
<Details>Did you know? The Healing Hand is composed of more than 3000 individual parts including over 2000 individual hands!</Details>
<Story>Tom Jackson developed an interest in metal and mechanical work when he was a boy. For many years, he worked as an auto and equipment mechanic. He enjoys working with a variety of metals including steel, brass and copper. Jackson&apos;s work also combines handmade form and technology. He uses CAD technology to create a design, but then forms, shapes, and colors each piece of metal individually.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>111</ID>
<Title>The Myths of Icarus:  A Father&apos;s Fear</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNjFSOGxrNG5xRjA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66566,45.4179</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>155</ID>
<Title>The Myths of Icarus:  As Deep as Heaven</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdFRZSk91Y3BkYVE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66564,45.41799</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>154</ID>
<Title>The Myths of Icarus:  Breathe Deeply</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWGdYOHdvY1dsd0E</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66565,45.41796</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>153</ID>
<Title>The Myths of Icarus:  He Had to Turn Away</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZURROU4wcEFOdW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66565,45.41793</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>46</ID>
<Title>The Three Graces</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Three armless women.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQ19FaWc2T2htQ1U</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.665041666667,45.4177083333333</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>457</ID>
<Title>The Visitor</Title>
<ArtistName>Geemon Xin Meng</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://www.xmsculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Sculpture creates connections between the imagination and the cosmos.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWl9rUVpQWldlbWM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.417491,-122.66359</LatLng>
<Sponsor>The Caldwell Family in thanks for Connor, Cameron &amp; Charlie</Sponsor>
<Materials>Fiberglass, concrete</Materials>
<Challenge>What other City has an iconic big blue bear in its public art collection?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape - the lack of negative space within the form of this sculpture adds to the exaggerated bulbous-ness.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Color - the bright blue helps the sculpture stand out amidst its landscaped surroundings.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Balance - the pudginess of the bear, especially weighted towards the bottom half in his pose, helps give the sculpture a feeling of balance.</Elements3>
<Details>&quot;I usually focus on the human condition, but sometimes a figure emerges from the clay whose persona is so compelling I almost expect it to speak. So it is with this bear, a visitor with something to say.&quot; - Geemon Xin Meng       If The Visitor could speak, what do you think it would say?</Details>
<Story>&quot;Geemon Xin Meng is the Director of the Vancouver Sculpture Studio. He is an internationally-recognized professional sculptor working within the tradition of classic, figurative sculpture. After having received a rigorous education at the Fine Art &amp; Design Central Academy of Beijing, he immigrated to Canada in 2004. A prolific artist with exceptional technical skill and vision, he focuses on developing a mastery of the medium while imbuing each sculpture with his own personal, contemporary vision. With over 25 years of experience as a sculptor, he has worked in a broad range of media — clay, fiberglass, marble, stainless steel, hammered copper, and bronze — creating both figurative and abstract works. In addition to teaching students at his Vancouver studio, Geemon is an Artist Mentor in the Master of Fine Arts program at Lesley University in Cambridge, MA. Geemon’s work has been shown in solo and group exhibits in Canada, China, the US and the UK.&quot;</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>73</ID>
<Title>The Way It Is</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Tall thin rectangular columns, polished flat stone, rough back with Stafford poetry.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRbGtHMTEzeVFpQ00</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.665316666667,45.4209138888889</LatLng>
<Materials>Basalt</Materials>
<Challenge>Why did the artist use stone as his medium?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - Vertical lines define the shape of this rectangular pillar.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture - The back is natural rough basalt; the front is chiseled and polished to a silky finish.</Elements2>
<Details>The poem was laid out on a rubber stencil that was adhered to the stone face; the following words were sandblasted into the polished surface.  Thin white paint was applied to the sandblasted indentations.</Details>
<Story>This sculpted pillar is a tribute to Lake Oswego resident William Stafford (1914-1993), Poet Laureate, who moved to Oregon to teach at Lewis and Clark College and published more than 65 volumes of poetry and prose during his lifetime.</Story>
<Style>Realistic</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>376</ID>
<Title>Tidal Pool</Title>
<ArtistName>Mary Ann Baker</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.maryannbaker.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>painted steel - bronze</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Rough rocks, tumbling waves, playful critters&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNXFadjlsMHNVTlU</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419854/-122.65662</LatLng>
<Materials>Painted steel, bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>How many sea creatures can you identify?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color: vivid red, yellow, blue, purple and green contrast bronze and natural rusted steel</Elements1>
<Elements2>Form: curves repeated to mimic the sea’s waves and ripples</Elements2>
<Details>Mary Ann Baker translates her ideas for sculptures into digital models using several computer programs. Following the computer designs, large sheets of steel are shaped, cut, colored and arranged to form her whimsical works of art.</Details>
<Story>Mary Ann Baker’s art frequently abstracts playful forms from nature—such as flowers, birds, and plants. Her used of bright color enlivens her public art sculptures. Recently, she recently moved her studio from California (San Francisco area) to New Mexico. Do you think this will change the subjects in her art?</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>48</ID>
<Title>Time and Space</Title>
<ArtistName>Stuart Jacobson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.stuartjacobsonsculptor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Black and white granite.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZWFnSFV5NU9iaTQ</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.723127777778,45.4129666666667</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>156</ID>
<Title>Torso (Nike as Victory)</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQ3pwMUFuX0tselk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66479,45.41795</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>388</ID>
<Title>Totem</Title>
<ArtistName>Travis Pond</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.steelpond.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRaHo0V1FveDlBQjg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.723389, 45.397139</LatLng>
<Materials>Repurposed Steel, Automotive Finish</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you identify the animals represented in this sculpture?  (Wolf, Beaver, Orca, Frog, Raven)</Challenge>
<Elements1>Contrast - colors and shapes</Elements1>
<Elements2>Lines - Curved &amp; vertical</Elements2>
<Details>The artist collects scrap metal and recombines the pieces into new forms.  Several of the objects in this sculpture were donated by the Fire Station and  location students.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture was commissioned by local business leaders in our community and citizens to watch over and protect our children and the firemen who protect us.</Story>
<Style>Representational</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>456</ID>
<Title>Transcendent</Title>
<ArtistName>Brian &quot;Huts&quot; Hutsebout</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://www.hutsebout.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Wood</Medium>
<Description>Boundless energy flowing through nature - a dance-like vitality.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRenhEc0pQd29FYzA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418229,-122.662952</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Cascade Sotheby&apos;s International Realty</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.cascadesothebysrealty.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Metal, wood, found materials</Materials>
<Challenge>Does this sculpture present recongizeable imagery? If so, what does it make you think of?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - the verticality of the steel pipes suggests upward movement.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - the way the elements are arranged achieves this element. The steel rods suggest stability and movement simultaneously.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Repetition/ryhthm/pattern - a regular repetition of elements can produce the look and feel of movement.</Elements3>
<Details>The wood at the tops of the rods is cedar. The cedar was deemed &quot;firewood,&quot; but the artist felt it still have more life. Each piece is individually turned by the artist and then given an oiled treatment to give it the warm golden glow.Transcendent will continue to transform within the outdoor elements, emulating the natural process of nature and transformation. Pieces of copper tubing were then applied to the top and bottom of the wooden bulbs. The &quot;stems&quot; are steel rods inserted into steel tubes. The rods have a patina to turn them dark brown where as the tubes are a shinier steel. The artist used several colors and layers of paint to bring color and vibrancy to the sculpture. To fabricate the banding, the artist experimented with nylon to model the steel. He then applied the final steel banding by heating and wrapping it around the steel tubes. Most of the material from the piece came from Metro&apos;s GLEAN* program. Http://recologyportland.com/oregon_art.php</Details>
<Story>&quot;Influenced by the living world, the artist’s goal is to contrast nature’s unequaled advances with the synthetic rapidity of contemporary human mass production. He intends to illuminate organic, temporal processes that are often overlooked and acknowledge the value inherent in nature. Through art, the artist endeavors to maintain an essential quality of craftsmanship to respect the balance humans should have with their surroundings. In order to maintain harmony with my environment, he works primarily with found or discarded objects. Unlike newly made items, every used material has a voice of its own: a history that has been collected through its existence. It is that history that compels him to reconstruct the clutter around us in a new way.&quot; - Brian Hutesbout</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>271</ID>
<Title>Trillium</Title>
<ArtistName>Matt Cartwright</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.cartwrightdesign.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Mixed Media</Medium>
<Description>Powder-coated steel, aluminum and acrylic.  The three leaves at the base of the sculpture are intended as seating.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBReWtwblJ6S21mN0U</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.660072222222,45.410375</LatLng>
<Materials>Powder-coated steel, aluminum with acrylic</Materials>
<Challenge>If the sculpture were painted one color, how would you still recognize the flower?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - separates the elements of the sculpture.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Shape - Triangular shape of a trillium plant&apos;s petals.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Space - Positive/Negative</Elements3>
<Details>Trillium is appropriately sited on the banks of the Willamette River in George Rogers Park.  Go sit on the bench and experience a quiet moment.</Details>
<Story>Trilliums are woodland wildflowers native to the temperate regions of North America that bloom in April and May.  If you pick the flower, the plant will not bloom again the next year.  If you pick the leaves as well, it will not re-grow fro many years.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2009&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2009</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>468</ID>
<Title>Under the Spell</Title>
<ArtistName>Ross Matteson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://mattesonsculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Wood</Medium>
<Description>A framing tribute to the spellbinding grace of the peregrine falcon!</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdVdDak9ka0pQT2M</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.41845,-122.667167</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Bonnie Cartwright</Sponsor>
<Materials>Bronze, Steel, Cedar</Materials>
<Challenge>What type of bird is perched on top of the gateway?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - Notice the soft and smooth texture of the bird. The falcon has a cobalt patina which gives it this smooth effect.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - Notice the detail in the carved cedar inserts in the upper portion of the steel cross section. The curved lines provide a more organic element to the black steel.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color - How does the use of black in this piece effect the  atmosphere?</Elements3>
<Details>The words on the top of the artwork read &quot;Under the Spell&quot; in runes, the elfish language from J.R.R. Tolkien novels.</Details>
<Story>This artwork is an actual gateway with a life size bronze of a peregrine falcon resting on top. As a life long falconer and lover of J. R. R. Tolkien&apos;s novels, birds and runes are very likely subjects in Matteson&apos;s sculpture.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realism&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realism</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>188</ID>
<Title>Untitled</Title>
<ArtistName>Bruce West</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.brucewestsculptures.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRVVYzUDFlRllfWWs</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.7279194,45.4112250</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What words would you use to describe this monumental piece?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Balance – Horizontal and vertical forms create a unified whole.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Pattern – “Quilt like” combinations.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Rhythm – Created by the placement of the forms</Elements3>
<Details>From afar the viewer wonders about the silver reflection of the sculpture; when the viewer nears the work, one sees that the reflection is enhanced by the artist’s burnishing of the stainless steel.</Details>
<Story>Bruce West is a retired professor of art from Lewis and Clark College who has been a part of the GWW for many years.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>475</ID>
<Title>Uprooted</Title>
<ArtistName>Andre Burgoyne</ArtistName>
<Medium>steel - concrete</Medium>
<Description>Relocation and Contentment
Concrete and Steel</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZmp1TmZnYTJwc3M</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419920/-122.669208</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lake Oswego Rotary</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.lakeoswegorotary.org/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Steel and concrete</Materials>
<Challenge>Notice that some of the lines in this piece are curved and some are straight. Why do you think the artist used the same materials to create different types of line? How else would you describe these lines? Do identify with one type of line over another?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Where is the lightest part of this sculpture? Where is it the heaviest? Next, think about scale. How does the artist use both balance and scale to create tension? What about motion? Does this work seem to be moving in a particular direction?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Look around the sculpture at both the built and the natural environment. How does this sculpture fit (or not) with its surroundings?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Use a sketchbook to draw some lines. How many different lines can you draw? Describe the kinds of lines you drew. Next, describe the types of lines the artist sculpted. Why do you think he created these types of lines?</Elements3>
<Details>The artist grew up in Montana, surrounded by land and sky. His work reveals the balance between contrasts: hard vs. soft; heavy vs. light; geometric vs. organic. The artist also has a background in carpentry, graphic design, and as an electrician.</Details>
<Story>This is the first piece of public art this sculptor has ever made!</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Nonrepresentational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Nonrepresentational</Style2>
<Misc>2017-2019 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>286</ID>
<Title>Vincent</Title>
<ArtistName>Keith Jellum</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.keithjellum.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Cast Bronze sculpture of the hare from Alice in Wonderland.  This is a 4 ft. cast edition of the original 8 ft. work that is located in Pendleton Park in Portland, OR.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRU2ZpN2pYSFh5a0E</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.426133/-122.668042</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Jennings Insurance</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.jenningsinsurance.com/index.htm#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Cast Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>Is this a rabbit or a hare?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture – look and feel of fur.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line – straight, vertical, curved.</Elements2>
<Details>Alert, looking at you, ready to move, whimsical</Details>
<Story>You are looking at a hare.  Hares make their nests above ground.  Rabbits nest underground.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realistic&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2010-2012 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
<Misc>2010-2012 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>160</ID>
<Title>Wall Fountain 1</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRd3VoV1VBeHlhZU0</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66499,45.41803</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>161</ID>
<Title>Wall Fountain 2</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUC01YVRwaWtKVms</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66504,45.41803</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>162</ID>
<Title>Wall Fountain 3</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRckRaajg0R2RqdG8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66531,45.41806</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>163</ID>
<Title>Wall Fountain 4</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBROEpVYnNFd2JiWnc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66537,45.41807</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>49</ID>
<Title>Water, Water, Water</Title>
<ArtistName>Bruce West</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.brucewestsculptures.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Flat mounted square panel with patterns of waves in steel.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRSGdzV3V2LXY2c1k</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.666722222222,45.4205722222222</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Why do you think this design was chosen for this fire hall location?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line – Can you find a straight line?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Rhythm – Balanced movement is created by the repetition of curved lines and scalloped shapes.</Elements2>
<Details>As an abstract work referencing reality, this sculpture presents a sense of water rushing from seven firemen’s hoses.</Details>
<Story>This work was commissioned by the City of Lake Oswego and added to the new fire hall in 1999.  We are fortunate to have a noted Northwest sculptor in our collection.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>278</ID>
<Title>Wormy Apple II</Title>
<ArtistName>Ed Humpherys</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.wallawallafoundry.com/exhibition/humpherys/</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Cast aluminum.  A three-dimensional, compositional representation of a wormy apple.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQ19FaWc2T2htQ1U</ImageLink>
<LatLng> -122.66401/45.41658</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>51</ID>
<Title>Zephyr</Title>
<ArtistName>Devin Laurence Field</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.devinlaurencefield.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Tall silver column topped by birds with outstretched wings.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRb3N0Wll4QnRzeTg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.663383333333,45.4182138888889</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Why does this sculpture belong near the lake in Lake Oswego?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line – wavy, defines movement of osprey and indicates the breeze blowing the banners.</Elements1>
<Elements2> </Elements2>
<Elements3> </Elements3>
<Details>This impressive osprey seems to be turning in flight to return to the lake for food.</Details>
<Story>Devin Laurence Field was awarded a commission to create One World One Dream, the sculpture outside the Bird’s Nest stadium in Beijing, China, for the 2008 Olympics.</Story>
<Style>Representational</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
  <ID>490</ID>
  <Title>Gear Box</Title>
  <ArtistName>Tim Mather</ArtistName>
  <ArtistWeb></ArtistWeb>
  <Description></Description>
  <ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0BweBioCa2upaSWlPaDQwTEZvTnc</ImageLink>
  <LatLng>45.398816,-122.733992</LatLng>
  <Materials>Recycled steel and antique gears</Materials>
  <Challenge>Do you recognize any of the gears on the sculpture? Can you imagine what their original use might have been?</Challenge>
  <Elements1> How does the artist use color here? What do you notice about how contrast is created between the recycled steel and the antique gears?  You might consider color, shape, and texture.</Elements1>
  <Elements2>How do you think this sculpture fits in with the other artwork installed at the Maintenance Center? How does Gear Box fit in with the natural and built environment?</Elements2>
  <Elements3>The big vertical beam that makes up this sculpture was recycled from the South Shore Bridge in Lake Oswego. Think about how artist can give new life to objects by using recycled materials.</Elements3>
  <Details>Tim&apos;s sculpture reflects a deep connection to history and place. A passionate collector of antique gears, several from his personal collection adorn this sculpture.</Details>
  <Story>The juxtaposition of different gears calls attention both to their distinct industrial functions and their stylistic variety.</Story>
  <Style>Abstract</Style>
  <Style2>Abstract</Style2>
  <Misc>Permanent Collection</Misc>
</PhoneData>
</dataroot>
