<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataroot xmlns:od="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:officedata" generated="2016-11-10T13:51:52">
<PhoneData>
<ID>54</ID>
<Title>Age of Iron</Title>
<ArtistName>Tom Hardy</ArtistName>
<Description>Ragged slabs of thin plates mounted/bolted to concrete base - 4 each.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBROHVaZVFpc1owdE0</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667277777778,45.4199861111111</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>458</ID>
<Title>Amyas &amp; Soleil</Title>
<ArtistName>Amyas Maestas</ArtistName>
<Description>I am intrigued how artwork can express my feelings, and the way it can inspire people.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNzNrWDBGUlJyems</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420576,-122.664104</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Step It Up Studios and Shirley &amp; Fred Baldwin</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.stepitupballroomsociety.com#http://www.stepitupballroomsociety.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>How old is the artist that created this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - how does the texture of the sculpture differ to emphasize different figurative elements on both Amyas &amp; Soleil?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - the upward movement of both Amyas &amp; Soleil&apos;s arms suggest joy and exuberance.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Contrast - how do the two sculptures differ?</Elements3>
<Details>Amyas Maestas, the artist who created these sculptures, is only 12 years old! He has had artwork on display in other cities such as Grand Junction, Colorado. He is Lake Oswego&apos;s youngest outdoor sculptor to date!</Details>
<Story>Amyas Maestas is Gallery Without Walls’ first youth sculptor to be accepted into the exhibition at the age of 12. This sculpture is a portrait of the artist and his sister.
As an artist and sculptor, Amyas’ goal is to bring a smile to the face of all who view his artwork. His sculpture is designed to be touched and move the viewer. It is meant to engage a lively conversation for everyone. The everyday simple things that surround us are his inspiration– his vision in creating art is to express a view of life that is joyful, playful, and fun.
As a sculptor, the “artist” experience in the public art realm has been very rewarding. Originally sculpted in clay, the finished work of art is cast in bronze. Thus, the art-work is suitable for outdoor presentation. Amyas’ work has had the honor of being chosen Best of Show and given the People’s Choice Award at the Art on the Corner Sculpture Exhibition in Grand Junction, CO.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>378</ID>
<Title>Angel Fish</Title>
<ArtistName>Marion-Lea Jamieson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.compositecreationssculpture.ca</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Powder-coated steel - concrete</Medium>
<Description>&quot;It reflects the interrelation &amp; interdependence of all life forms.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Jamieson-Race_AngelFish.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.664077777778,45.4205805555556</LatLng>
<Materials>Powder-coated Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How is Angel Fish like and unlike a mermaid?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color – Monochromatic color encourages viewer to examine the form</Elements1>
<Elements2>Shape – Simplified forms unite to form a complex whole</Elements2>
<Details>Human-animal hybrids are frequent subjects in art, literature and mythology.  Jamieson and Race have jointly explored this rich background in the creation of Angel Fish.</Details>
<Story>This husband/wife team explores hybrid themes in drawings and paintings that they translate into maquettes (small models) and then into their large-scale works.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>403</ID>
<Title>Angel Flight</Title>
<ArtistName>Jim Willis</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jimwillis-studio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>mahogany &amp; copper leaf - Metal</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Angel Flight, A tribute to the brave who return our fallen &amp; wounded warriors home&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Willis-Angel-Flight.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66538579141633, 45.420115831086406</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Graham’s Book and Stationery</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>http://www.facebook.com/pages/Grahams-Stationery/145076232194065?ref=stream&amp;hc_location=timeline#http://www.facebook.com/pages/Grahams-Stationery/145076232194065?ref=stream&amp;hc_location=timeline#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Mahogany, copper, wood</Materials>
<Challenge>What aspects of this sculpture are reflected in the title?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Shape - Organic</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Texture - Wood grain &amp; grooves creating a sense of wings and cloth</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Line - Straight, curved, diagonal</Elements3>
<Details>Willis uses organic forms as a starting point.  From sketches he glues sections of hardwoods together into his general designed shape and then begins removing material with hand and power tools.  This is when he feels he is most creative.</Details>
<Story>Angel Flight is the name given to a group or organization who arranges free transportation for patients or family members in need.  Jim Willis created Angel Flight as a tribute to the brave who return from combat our fallen and wounded warriors.  He transforms wood and metal into a harmonious balance of color, form and materials.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>361</ID>
<Title>Angkor I</Title>
<ArtistName>Lee Kelly</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.leekellysculpture.net</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTjJyVm9ESEloMEk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66468,45.41775</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What is your initial reaction to Angkor I?  Do you see size, materials or shapes as you first begin looking at the work?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shapes:  Rectangle, square and triangle.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line:  Straight lines move ones eyes from the base to the top and upward.  These lines communicate a sense of the inherent strength of the sculpture.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Balance:  Tripod base, repetition of shapes</Elements3>
<Details>•	Burnishing the steel with a metal sander creates a texture that sparkles in the sunlight.  
•	Note the vertical welded lines in the horizontal central beam.
•	The use of hollow fabricated forms is used to create volume and mass. 
•	This abstract form is framed by the realism of nature’s sky, lake and trees.</Details>
<Story>Lee Kelly’s travels to Nepal and other sites influenced many of his works of the 1980’s and 1990’s.  Lee Kelly has loaned Angkor I to the Arts Council of Lake Oswego and the community for a limited time.  We are fortunate to be able to showcase this nationally and internationally known public artist.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>60</ID>
<Title>Anillos</Title>
<ArtistName>Maria Wickwire</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.mariawickwire.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Ceramic sculpture - Metal</Medium>
<Description>Camel color clay figure of sitting nude with bands of lines surrounding her.  &apos;Mummy-like&apos; figure.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUGVXNXVJMTd4bGs</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.664177777778,45.4191611111111</LatLng>
<Materials>High-fired ceramic clay</Materials>
<Challenge>What do you think the dark lines represent?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture – Course.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Pattern – repeated rings.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line – curved and repeated</Elements3>
<Details>The human form has no straight lines. Coil method of construction, layer upon layer.</Details>
<Story>The artist states, ”The ringed markings on Anillos evokes the annual rings which show the history of an individual tree, including fire, famine, flood, and flourishing.  Like trees, our life experiences are written in the cells of our bodies.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2007&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2007</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>461</ID>
<Title>Anna</Title>
<ArtistName>Julian Voss-Andreae</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://julianvossandreae.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>The human figure reduced to a few hundred triangular planes, welded from stainless steel.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRbTVoU1NvQUFiM0E</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419592,-122.665143</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lake Oswego Vision Clinic</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://lakeoswegoeyes.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How many stainless steel pieces make up Anna?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape - Notice how the use of individual triangles to fabricate this sculpture adds to geometry of the overall form.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Light - The stainless steel lightly textured finish creates reflective patterns throughout the sculpture.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Unity - Notice how the repetition of triangular forms creates an overall visual unity of the sculpture.</Elements3>
<Details>Anna is made up of appoximately 600 stainless steel triangles welded together to form this sculpture.</Details>
<Story>Julian Voss-Andreae is a German sculptor based in Portland, OR. Starting out as a painter, he changed courses and studied physics, mathematics and philosophy at Universities. Voss-Andreae pursued his graduate research in quantam physics. He moved to the US to study schulpture at the Pacific Northwest College of Art from where he graduated in 2004. Voss-Andreae&apos;s work, often inspired by his background in science, has captured the attention of multiple instutiuions in the US and abroad.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>419</ID>
<Title>Ascending Leaves</Title>
<ArtistName>Bruce West</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.brucewestsculptures.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>leaves blowing in the wind really enjoy the ride

Sponsored by Don Nussmeier</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-ascending-leaves.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419598,-122.665197</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Don Nussmeier</Sponsor>
<Materials>Burnished stainless steel</Materials>
<Challenge>If not leaves, what else does this sculpture remind you of?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - The curved and vertical lines gives the illusion of upward movement</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture - Notice the texture of the leaves from the burnishing process</Elements2>
<Elements3>Repetition/Rhythm/Pattern - Repetition of leaves produces the feel of movement as well</Elements3>
<Details>From afar the viewer wonders about the silver reflection of the sculpture; when the viewer nears the work, one sees that the reflection is enhanced by the artist&apos;s burnishing of the stainless steel.</Details>
<Story>Bruce West is a retired professor of art from Lewis and Clark College who has been a part of the GWW for many years.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>440</ID>
<Title>Aspens</Title>
<ArtistName>Reven Swanson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.revenswanson.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;A pleasant walk through the woods under a canopy, flickering &amp; dancing.&quot;

Sponsored by the Lake Oswego Rotary Club</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRbVFsWUhjbW5yc1k</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419920,-122.669208</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lake Oswego Rotary Club</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.lakeoswegorotary.org#http://www.lakeoswegorotary.org#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Mild steel, powder-coat and painted enamel</Materials>
<Challenge>An Aspen Tree is State Tree of which State? (hint: The State has 4 letters in its name.)</Challenge>
<Elements1>Repetition/Rythym/Patterns - 3 similar forms are repeated to give the effect of a grove of trees or one large tree.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Color - the bright use of color enhances the playful quality of the sculpture and reflects the artist&apos;s extensive knowledge of powder-coating.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - the curved line that makes up the stem gives the piece movement.</Elements3>
<Details>Many of the artist&apos;s artworks are kinetic, meaning they move when interacted with. In this case, Aspens is a wind-powered sculpture.</Details>
<Story>As an artist whose childhood was largely spent in the great outdoors of Colorado, this work is an ode to her memory of connecting with nature. Watching the subtle movement of the kinetic sculpture as the &quot;leaves&quot; catch the wind, the artist invites us into her memory of peering through the woods to discover a colorful canopy.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>404</ID>
<Title>Audrey</Title>
<ArtistName>Guy Angelo Wilson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.guyangelowilson.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Bronze - Bronze</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Audrey&quot; Audrey was inspired by my youngest daughter and a passage from Henry David Thoreau:  
            &quot; I am monarch of all that I survey&quot;.</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Wilson-Audrey.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66519866895179, 45.42081038937477</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>Look at Audrey in relation to her location. How does she relate to the basalt column across the street?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Color - Muted hues</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Shape - Human frm, 	Balance - Bilateral symmetry</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Texture - Dress, hair, laurel wreath, skin</Elements3>
<Details>Cast in bronze from a polyurethane rubber mold, the surface is then treated with oxides to create the various colors of the bronze (patina).</Details>
<Story>Guy Wilson’s daughter was the model for this sculpture.  She was five years old at the time and wanted to wear her clogs (one of many pair she wore all the time).  He placed the laurel wreath on her head remembering a quote from Henry David Thoreau, “I am monarch of all that I survey.”  His sculpting experience is vast; he has done work for Disney, DreamWorks, HBO, 20th Century Fox and many others.  Also extensive is his teaching career spanning twenty-five plus years.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realistic&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>264</ID>
<Title>August Trunk</Title>
<ArtistName>Alisa Formway Roe</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.afroemetalwork.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRaGJ3a2ozXzhiQVk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.719786,45.409992</LatLng>
<Materials>Welded mild steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Is this elephant young or old?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Space - positive and negative.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Shape – size of parts give a sense of strength &amp; power.</Elements2>
<Details>Majestic head, broken tusk, and organic form of ears</Details>
<Story>A trip to Africa motivated the artist to sculpt an elephant who could be in the august season of his life, an august (wise) animal or the object of abuse or all of the above.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2011&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2011</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>418</ID>
<Title>Bartholomew the Black Rhino</Title>
<ArtistName>Jud Turner</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.judturner.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Welded steel - recycled materials</Medium>
<Description>Cognitive provocation through visual seduction

Sponsored by Don Caldwell</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-bartholomew.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.41996,-122.668061</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Don Caldwell &amp; Family</Sponsor>
<Materials>Welded steel, recycled materials</Materials>
<Challenge>Do you recognized any of the steel pieces that make up Bartholomew? </Challenge>
<Elements1>Form - The artist creates the form of the Rhino from single recycled steel elements</Elements1>
<Elements2>Emphasis - Given to the Rhino’s horn</Elements2>
<Elements3>Unity - Created through the substructure and surface elements</Elements3>
<Details>The bird riding on Bartholomew is called an Oxpecker oftentimes accompanies Rhinos in the wild in the same way.</Details>
<Story>The artist focuses on recycling and repurposing found objects to create sculptures which appear as a unified whole while maintaining aspects of the individual objects. His subject matter oftentimes makes his artwork more approachable for all ages. The artist used mostly found objects form recycled motorcycle and car parts to create Bartholomew.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>225</ID>
<Title>Bearly About</Title>
<ArtistName>Steve Tyree</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.tyreesculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>3 bears - Bronze sculpture 
Mother bear - 50&quot; x 18&quot; x 28&quot;
Baby bear1 - 20&quot; x 14&quot; x 8&quot;
Baby bear2 - 15&quot; x 20&quot; x 14&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZks1SDNpTVdQQnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6671,45.4242333333333</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>What&apos;s going on between the mother bear and her cubs?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Rhythm - Implied movement of the figures moves the viewer&apos;s eye from bear to bear.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - Triangular placement of figures.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - Curvilinear</Elements3>
<Details>Placement of the bears in the grass creates a natural environment for these animals.</Details>
<Story>Children visiting the library fell in love with the bears from the moment they were installed.  A jar for pennies was placed in the library and a collection was begun to buy the bears.  The artist, Steve Tyree, was so touched by this effort on the part of the children of Lake Oswego that he donated the bears to the community.</Story>
<Style>Realistic</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>413</ID>
<Title>Ben</Title>
<ArtistName>Dore Capitani</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.doresmountainartgarden.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Powder-coated steel - copper sparkle coating</Medium>
<Description>Suddenly..an idea!!!


Sponsored by Bill and Barbara Warner</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-ben.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.417493,-122.663573</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Bill and Barbara Warner</Sponsor>
<Materials>Powder-coated steel, copper sparkle coating</Materials>
<Challenge>Why do you think the artist named this sculpture Ben?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - The brightly colored powder-coating adds vibrancy and whimsy to the artwork</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - The curved stem suggests movement and creates a more interesting form</Elements2>
<Elements3>Emphasis - Because of the emphasis on the flower, your eye moves to the top of the sculpture.</Elements3>
<Details>Capitani has said that he has a fascination with petroglyphs (rock carvings) and that much of his art is inspired by this. If you look upwards towards the top of the sculpture, you will notice patterning in the steel cut outs that somewhat resemble these petroglyphs.</Details>
<Story>With a past as a mechanical engineer, Capitani’s experiences have helped him learn to blend sharp metal edges with fluid motion. He cuts his own metal and uses and ironworker to get the shapes and forms he wants. Then he uses custom-made dies to find the right shape. After he’s got the form, he welds the patterns together and then powder-coats if the sculpture is going to have a finish. Capitani says, “It’s 95 percent preparation and 5% application. He is extremely hands on with the artwork, cutting and bending the steel himself (the artist always uses new metal) and uses custom-made dies to get the shape he wants. Then he welds, which, as you can see from the shape on the top of the sculpture, is tricky with a spherical shape.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>56</ID>
<Title>Blue Light Tower</Title>
<ArtistName>Joel Cottet</ArtistName>
<Description>Tower is made of several sculptural ceramic pieces anchored together to form a column.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRSGJNcHJ4VGUyTGs</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.742897222222,45.417625</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>3</ID>
<Title>Bread Upon the Water</Title>
<ArtistName>Jerry Joslin</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.joslinstudios.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>This sculpture of three children feeding ducks is a familiar Lake Oswego scene.  It is cast 3/4 the size conceived by the artist.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNmswZ3FfVTNGTUk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667861111111,45.4195972222222</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>How realistic are the figures?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Balance - achieved by triangular placement of the figures.</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Line - the diagonals and curves create gesture, action and movement.</Elements2>
<Details>The positions of human figures with the duck create a story line.</Details>
<Story>This portrayal of a common scene in Lake Oswego of children feeding ducks evokes childhood memories for many of us.</Story>
<Style>Realistic</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>446</ID>
<Title>Breaktime</Title>
<ArtistName>Anthony Teixeira</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.anthonyteixeira.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Anthony uses familiar objects to invoke personal reflection.&quot;

Sponsored by Jeff &amp; Teresa Metke, Metke Remodeling &amp; Luxury Homes</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdzNCTDJ5ZDNfaHc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418527,-122.667482</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Jeff &amp; Teresa Metke, Metke Remodeling &amp; Luxury Homes</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>remodelerportlandoregon.com#http://remodelerportlandoregon.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Cast aluminum, steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What do you think is the artist&apos;s meaning behind representing a hammer with a broken handle and nails that are bent?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - the hammer is fabricated from cast aluminum; the textured and sanded coating is what makes the aluminum look so much like wood.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line- notice how the lines in the hammer help to create the illusion of wood.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Emphasis - the oversized hammer head focuses the viewer&apos;s eye towards the bottom of the sculpture, and the natural movement upwards towards the tip of the broken handle allows  for overall unity.</Elements3>
<Details>This sculpture is made of steel and cast aluminum coated to look like wood over a series of many coats. The artist&apos;s sculptures often use recognizeable objects to encourage the viewer&apos;s familiarity and contemplation with the object.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture is about perseverance. Despite the broken handle of the hammer, the title suggests that the break is only a temporary obstacle to overcome.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>415</ID>
<Title>Capricorn</Title>
<ArtistName>Robert Foster</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.roberthfoster.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Bronze - aluminum pedestal</Medium>
<Description>The Zodiac sign Capricorn portrayed as a classic sculpture on a classic pedestal

Sponsored by Accessories from the Heart</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-capricorn.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419423,-122.665678</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Accessories from the Heart</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.accessoriesfromtheheart.com#http://www.accessoriesfromtheheart.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Bronze with aluminum pedestal</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you figure out what the cornucopia earring references? Hint: It comes from Greek mythology.</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - Notice the texture of the horns and the hair on the face</Elements1>
<Elements2>Repetition/Rhythm/Pattern - The repetition of detailed marks creates a pattern of design</Elements2>
<Elements3>Unity - The shiny surface of both the sculpture and the pedestal give a feeling of unity to the entire installation.</Elements3>
<Details>If you look closely at the sculpture, you will notice an earring on Capricorn. The earring resembles a cornucopia (Horn of Plenty), referencing Greek mythology. This earring was made through taking a mold of the artist’s wife’s brooch and then cast in bronze using the lost wax technique.</Details>
<Story>Capricorn is the Zodiac sign for the sun and has been represented by both the Horn of Plenty and the goat. The Horn of Plenty is the horn of the goat Amalthea who was Zeus’ baby nurse in Greek mythology. When Zeus was born, his mother, Rhea, wanted to protect him from his father, Cronos, who had eaten the rest of the children in order to protect himself from deposing him. Rhea was successful in tricking Cronos into eating a stone that he thought was a baby while Rhea hid Zeus in a cave, protected and raised by Amalthea, a magical goat. The Horn of Plenty is an ancient Greek symbol of the harvest and has been reinterpreted many times. Foster’s decision to represent Capricorn as a stylized bust on a classic pedestal pays homage to its mythological roots.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>442</ID>
<Title>Clackamas</Title>
<ArtistName>Mike Suri</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.suriiron.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Three plates pressed into a vessel form.&quot;

Sponsored by Johnstone Financial Advisors</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdldUR2FaTVB5Tk0</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418766,-122.66709</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Johnstone Financial Advisors</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.johnstonefinancialadvisors.com#http://www.johnstonefinancialadvisors.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Weathering steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How many individual pieces of steel make up this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Space - three steel plates come together to create both positive and negative space.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - although the sculpture is not symmetrical, the artist plays with balance by extending the oar on one side of the sculpture.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture- because the artist uses weathering steel, the texture will continue to transform through the interaction with natural elements.</Elements3>
<Details>Suri acquired the steel plates while working as a demonstrator at Clackamas County Community College. They are remnants not only of our region&apos;s industry, but also the artist&apos;s life and career.</Details>
<Story>Clackamas is three steel plates gently shaped and nestled together into vessel form.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>349</ID>
<Title>Cloud Totem</Title>
<ArtistName>Riis Burwell</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.riisburwell.com/</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRRTd2dlBETk9YbTA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.666894,45.4184</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>Do you find the exterior or the interior shape more interesting?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line – Curved, vertical lines carry viewer’s eye from bottom to top.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Space – Positive and negative.</Elements2>
<Details>Riis Burwell’s sculpture imparts a sense of energy through juxtaposition of form and line.  He begins with a maquette (model) that he hand fabricates into the larger final sculpture.  Move from facing the sculpture to the side of the sculpture; how does it change?</Details>
<Story>“My sculpture draws its vitality from my reverence for nature and my fascination with the opposing forces of geometry that underlie the structure of the physical world.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2011-2013 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2011-2013 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>141</ID>
<Title>Complement II</Title>
<ArtistName>Merrilee Moore</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.merrileemoore.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>2 pieces:
- Stainless steel free-form sculpture, burnished (62&quot;high x 33&quot; wide x 18&quot; deep)
- Stainless steel cage of colored glass balls (70&quot; high x 33&quot; wide x 18&quot; deep)</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBReEhuNnBPM01uM3M</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.408146,-122.724225</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless steel, glass</Materials>
<Challenge>How are the two parts different?  How are they similar?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color – creates the emotion of joy and gives rhythm &amp; variety to the work.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Space – positive &amp; negative.</Elements2>
<Details>Fabricated Steel.  Each glass ball is hand blown by the artist.</Details>
<Story>Each piece is individually unique and can stand on its own; yet when they are placed together, they create a perfect “complement” to one another.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2008&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2008</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>398</ID>
<Title>Contrapposto</Title>
<ArtistName>Francisco Salgado</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.franciscosalgado.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>painted steel - steel</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Waiting for something to happen&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Salgado-Contrapposto.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6658,45.4181416666667</LatLng>
<Materials>Painted steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you copy this figure’s pose?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Color - Monochrome exterior focuses viewer on the pose</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Shape – Organic form of the human body contrasts with the  ribbons of metal</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Line - Vertical and curved</Elements3>
<Details>“Contrappasto” is an Italian word for counter position, or counter balance, resulting a in a figure standing with most of its weight on one foot.  Notice the position of the figure’s hips and shoulders—the opposite hip and shoulder are high, and the corresponding opposites are low, creating an X-shaped pattern in the pose.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture is a figurative abstract presented with playful energy.  Salgado captures this same energy when doing portraits in his photography studio in Sellwood, OR.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>434</ID>
<Title>Crossroad of Eternity</Title>
<ArtistName>Dave Haslett</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.orcastone.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>NW Granite - NW Basalt</Medium>
<Description>&quot;The concept of eternity or infinite time typically eludes the grasp of human comprehension. Crossroad of Eternity presents the idea of a continuance of time without beginning or end which at some point a vital decision must be made.&quot;

Sponsored by Paul &amp; Teri Graham</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTlVkbnlNcmVoWFU</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420182,-122.66527</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Paul &amp; Teri Graham</Sponsor>
<Materials>NW Granite on NW Basalt</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you name the two types of stone used to fabricate this sculpture? In what region of the US can you find these types of stone?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - of the smooth, polished stone versus the incised lines that have not been polished. Texture of the granite versus the Basalt.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - notice how the incised lines lead the viewers eye into the stone and move you up and down, leading the viewer on a visual journey.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Space - the negative space in this sculpture lightens the load of stone and gives the viewer&apos;s eye a visual break.</Elements3>
<Details>This sculpture was displayed for the first time in the Lan Su Chinese Garden in NW Portland. Since then it has been re-worked into its present (and complete) final form.</Details>
<Story>Haslett&apos;s &apos;Vertebra&apos; series relates to bone and its marvelous structural arrangement representing an interlocking system of strength and beauty. Dinosaur and whale bones are the main influence of works in this series.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>370</ID>
<Title>Crows</Title>
<ArtistName>Tamar Assaf</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.tamarassaf.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Synanthropic species flourish in response to human habitat expansion.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRR2hOaUxrT2VpUTA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6641, 45.420783</LatLng>
<Materials>High-fired Ceramic</Materials>
<Challenge>How do these clay crows imitate real crows in their color, form and location?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Repetition – Placement:  Rhythm and balance move your eyes across the wire.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Form:  Conical</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color:  Blackened birds</Elements3>
<Details>Tamar Assaf has made these birds out of clay on a potter’s wheel.  The shaped form is then shaved with a vegetable peeler, sanded and then fired in a kiln.  The red hot birds are removed and placed in a pile of paper that bursts into flames.  She covers the fire with a pot thereby removing the oxygen and blackening the crows.</Details>
<Story>“Crows are remarkably intelligent. They have learned to utilize the human environment to their benefit – using bread crumbs as fishing bait and dropping nuts into heavy traffic for cars to crush to expose the inner core for their food.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>447</ID>
<Title>Cultus Ehkahnam</Title>
<ArtistName>Anthony Heinz May</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.anthonyheinzmay.wix.com/art</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Upcycled while simultaneously fridded by the devices of time.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRVWJzZ3lwMUE3NXc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419854,-122.666806</LatLng>
<Materials>River Birch</Materials>
<Challenge>What type of tree is this sculpture made from? Does this tree grow in Lake Oswego?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - the texture of the bark enhances the natural but fragile quality of this sculpture.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - the cross hatched lines on the upper part of the sculpture creates a puzzle-like texture and form that drives the complexity of the work and prompts questions about its fabrication.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Value/light - by cutting the pieces of the tree in such a way as to expose the inside of the tree and the lighter value of the wood, viewers can see how the bark changes from the exterior of the tree to the interior.</Elements3>
<Details>Cultus Ehkahnam is a phrase derived from Chinook jargon. Cultus = worthless (dull or pedantic); ehkahnam = tale or story.</Details>
<Story>The tree used to fabricate this sculpture came from the City of Lake Oswego&apos;s tree cutting permit process. The sculpture is made from a branch of a River Birch tree: chopped, sculpted and reconfigured into this beautiful work of art.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>50</ID>
<Title>Dream</Title>
<ArtistName>Guruhans Kroesen</ArtistName>
<Description>A tree with an apple hanging from one of the branches.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRemlHb2pwdXFYUzA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.7175917,45.4123028</LatLng>
<Materials>Fabricated Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Why do you think the artist chose to have only one apple on the tree?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color – highlights the red apple.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Rhythm – The vertical line is offset by the dancing curves that bisect it.</Elements2>
<Details>The flat planes of the surfaces give a feel of modernity to this work.</Details>
<Story>Many people associate the red apple as an apple for the teacher at the elementary school in the background, but the artist Guruhan Krossen says it “depicts our destiny, a path for life to stroll upon – which will guide you to your dream.”</Story>
<Style>Representational</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>390</ID>
<Title>Ebb Tide</Title>
<ArtistName>Olinka Broadfoot</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.olinkabroadfootgallery.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>bronze - clay</Medium>
<Description>&quot;The in-between moment....when anything is possible&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Broadfoot-Ebb-Tide.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667641666667,45.4196055555556</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze, clay brick</Materials>
<Challenge>Given the title of the sculpture, how does this piece relate to the ocean and its tides?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Line - Curved creating a sense of movement</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Color - Enhanced by its muted earth tones this is an organic free form that seems to float</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Texture – Contrasting textures in the bronze and the clay bricks</Elements3>
<Details>The skill of the artist is evident as she makes bronze appear wavy and lyrical like seaweeds in an ocean.  The top is bronze cast from a mold while the base is an example of relief sculpture—clay is added to bricks and hardened in the firing process.</Details>
<Story>Olinka Broadfoot left Prague, Czech Republic, in 1948 at age four, two days before the Communist takeover.  Via Argentina she came to the United States—New York, Utah and then Oregon—where she became a U.S. citizen and found her home and career in 2D and 3D art.  She returns annually to the Czech Republic to teach students from all over the world at a brick factory where they create art from clay roofing material.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>395</ID>
<Title>Egg</Title>
<ArtistName>James Lapp</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jameslapp.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Stainless steel - concrete pad</Medium>
<Description>&quot;To be on the inside looking out or not to be on the outside looking in&quot;


People&apos;s Choice Nominee 2014</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Lapp-Egg.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6668,45.4198138888889</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Morgan Stanley - Lake Oswego Branch</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.morganstanley.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Where would you begin creating this egg – top, bottom or middle?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Color - Stainless surface reflects sunlight, much like cut crystal reflects light</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Line - Geometric pieces are combined into an oval shape that has a sense of rhythm and balance</Elements2>
<Details>James Lapp created Egg in pieces.  He formed a template of curved wood on which he laid and welded the stainless wire.  When he had enough pieces to make the egg, he hung them from a pulley and began welding the larger sections together.  He welded inside and out; then he smoothed each weld.  Note how many welds hold this egg together.</Details>
<Story>Fabulous Egg is a part of a small series of Lapp’s work in which simple everyday objects are enlarged to impressive scale. The ability to see the surface and through the sculpture at the same time creates an intriguing viewing experience. This Washington state artist has honed his skills since his first solo exhibit in 1999.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>409</ID>
<Title>Emerald Springs</Title>
<ArtistName>Don Anderson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://www.applewoodfarmstudios.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Stainless steel - copper</Medium>
<Description>Nominated for People&apos;s Choice 2015</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-emerald-springs.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419729,-122.666485</LatLng>
<Sponsor>World Class Wines &amp; Step It Up Studios</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.worldclasswinesoregon.com; www.stepitupballroomsociety.com#http://www.worldclasswinesoregon.com; www.stepitupballroomsociety.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel, copper, metamorphic sandstone</Materials>
<Challenge>What does the curved shape at the top of the sculpture remind you of?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture—juxtaposition of sandstone to smooth copper and steel</Elements1>
<Elements2>Shape—positive/negative</Elements2>
<Elements3>Balance—not symmetrical, but placement of crescent form adds balance to the artwork</Elements3>
<Details>This artwork falls under the artist’s main exploration, the observation of fractals and recurring energy themes (wind, heat and waves).  The artist sees fractals as both illuminating the beauty of the earth and as a reflection of our lives’ as humans and their cyclical nature.</Details>
<Story>As a professional pipe welder, artist Don Anderson works largely in steel. Because of his upbringing in Kansas, wind has always been a major form of inspiration. With a large conceptual focus on fractals created in the natural world, Anderson uses both hand crafted elements of metal and natural elements to enhance each artwork conceptually.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>441</ID>
<Title>Enterprise</Title>
<ArtistName>Jim Scott</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>gr8scottdesign.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Pushing balance and gravity to their extremes.&quot;

Sponsored by Kathi Noles</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWVdPbG1WdTY5QWs</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.417607,-122.663522</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Kathi Noles</Sponsor>
<Materials>Painted steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How many intersecting planes does this sculpture have?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - the red color enhances the visibility of the sculpture. Why do you think he chose red?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - the sculpture is engineered to balance without the baseplate.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Form - the form is very geometric, and illuminates the artist&apos;s engineering capabilities.</Elements3>
<Details>Each sculpture is balanced before the artist attaches the baseplate.</Details>
<Story>Jim Scott&apos;s sculptures, such as Enterprise, explore studies in gravity and balance. As a product designer and process design engineer, Scott has been pursuing the exploration of positive and negative shapes that are machine-created. According to the artist, these sculptures rely on the strength of the materials to reconcile mass with gravity.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>467</ID>
<Title>Equilibrium</Title>
<ArtistName>Francisco Salgado</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.franciscosalgado.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Equilibrium: a state of physical balance of geometric forms.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWWthNTBvQndsRHM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419572,-122.667585</LatLng>
<Sponsor>The Vessely Family in honor of Jon C. Vessely, M.D.</Sponsor>
<Materials>Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How many negative spaces do you count within this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - vibrant colors help the sculpture stand out from its surroundings.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - The way the elements are arranged to create a feeling of stability.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Shape/Form - A shape is a self-contained defined area of geometric or organic form. A positive form automatically creates a negative form.</Elements3>
<Details>All three of Salgado&apos;s sculptures that have been a part of Lake Oswego&apos;s Gallery Without Walls have featured the color yellow.</Details>
<Story>Salgado &quot;focuses on creating public art works that  create a sense of place with an aura of playfulness and a nod to  inclusion.&quot;</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>285</ID>
<Title>Fairy Tree</Title>
<ArtistName>John Uppinghouse</ArtistName>
<Description>Structural concrete over a welded steel core.  The concrete is treated with an acryclic filler to make it smooth and slick.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTldJT1ZRX05wb3c</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66112,45.41143</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>460</ID>
<Title>Fat Tire #3</Title>
<ArtistName>Lance Carleton</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.itsallartt.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>I am a contemporary artist creating eclectic sculpture.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRekdmbDdRMlBBekU</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419505,-122.664456</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lakeside Bicycles in loving memory of Carol &amp; Dr. Seymour Haber, the Pastry Fairies</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>lakeside-bikes.com#http://lakeside-bikes.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Steel, copper, ceramics</Materials>
<Challenge>What is the most famous bike race in the world?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Space - The stylized and overexaggerated form of the bicycle allows for a large contrast of positive and negative space.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - How do the exaggerated lines add to the whimsical character of the artwork?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Balance - Despite it&apos;s large size, the sculpture retains complete balance.</Elements3>
<Details>The presence of Fat Tire in the Lake Oswego community reflects that its commitment to a green environment through eco-friendly conveyances. *Interaction with sculptures is at your own risk.</Details>
<Story>&quot;The fat tire series brings a smaile to everyone from age three to ninety-three. Almost everyone can visualize a moment or period in their present or past where this 2 wheel conveyance has provided pleasure and joy in their life.&quot; - Lance Carleton</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>59</ID>
<Title>First Footsteps</Title>
<ArtistName>Jim Demetro</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jimdemetro.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Life size piece of Mom holding baby&apos;s hands while baby is taking its first steps.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQTI0QWJhdTVGUUE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667730555556,45.4199138888889</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Bank of America</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#https://www.bankofamerica.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Cast Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>Why do you think the mother and child are smiling?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Texture - see it in the skin, clothing and hair</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Line - the slanted lines of the bodies allow the viewer to understand what is occurring.</Elements2>
<Details>Patina - observe the color variation.  Face - note the expressive emotion of the mother and child.</Details>
<Story>Portrays happiness at the thrilling moment of a child’s first steps.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realistic&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2004&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2004</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>63</ID>
<Title>Fish Banners</Title>
<ArtistName>Thomas Augustine</ArtistName>
<Description>Three fish banners mounted on street lights.  Auto paint on metal.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNGRzUk5oR3A4d2c</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66239,45.4211</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>4</ID>
<Title>Fortuna</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Fountain - armless woman with basket on head.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZ2NDVllmUEN5SVE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.664516666667,45.41805</LatLng>
<Materials>Bronze, basalt, iron</Materials>
<Challenge>Find recognizable objects in the rock pile from which the figure, Fortuna, arises.</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line – vertical lines move the eye upward.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Contrast – between the circular basket &amp; rectangular body.</Elements2>
<Details>The water basket on the head of the figure is based on ancient Mayan sculptures.  Her body is patterned after ancient Greek and Roman sculptures that today no longer have their arms.</Details>
<Story>The artist was inspired by Fortuna, the Roman goddess of fortune and good luck.  She rises from a midden (ancient dumpsite) filled with debris.</Story>
<Style>Representational</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>469</ID>
<Title>Genesis</Title>
<ArtistName>Sharon Warman Agnor</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.sharonagnor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Glass</Medium>
<Description>Genesis links ancient creation stories and the human compulsion to make.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBReDRwQUhIQ3hlcTA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419518,-122.666579</LatLng>
<Sponsor>KeyBank</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.key.com#http://www.key.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel, kilncast glass</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you name any of the other artworks the artist, Sharon Warman Agnor, has had in the Gallery Without Walls collection prior to Genesis?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - Notice how the vertical lines move your eye upwards towards the &quot;eye&quot; of the sculpture.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Color - How many colors are included in the &quot;eye&quot; of the sculpture?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture - There are mutliple textures working together to create this sculpture: the smooth stainless steel, the glossy glass, and the textured sparkle glass.</Elements3>
<Details>The artist was inspired by the creation story (the book of Genesis) in the Bible.</Details>
<Story>&quot;Where does the ability to create come from? It seems to be within our human DNA to be makers, solvers, creators. This sculpture is my personal exploration into the origins of creativity and art itself. In &quot;Genesis&quot; there is a cosmic theme, linking ancient creation stories to the human compulsion to create. Here, steel, bronze and glass join with light, darkness, color and the cosmos to probe this marvelous human question.&quot; - Sharon Warman Agnor</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016 - 2018 Rotating Exhibition&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016 - 2018 Rotating Exhibition</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>58</ID>
<Title>Going for Your Vision</Title>
<ArtistName>Alisa Looney</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.alisalooney.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Standing figure in red with extended arms.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRYi1XNEVhVEI2SFk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.661361111111,45.4238333333333</LatLng>
<Materials>Powder coated steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Try to find a straight line.</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - Overall red color brings focus to the sculpture as a whole.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - Diagonal and curvilinear.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Pattern - Cut-out spirals</Elements3>
<Details>Spiral designs symbolize the energy of the body, muscle structure and freedom of movement.  The viewers&apos; eyes move with the sculpture.  Rather than breaking up the piece, the spiral pattern unifies it.</Details>
<Story>In Alisa Looney&apos;s words, the sculpture represents the determination, energy and action it takes to go after your life&apos;s dream.  The color red reflects the fire in your belly when you are moved into action toward your greatest vision.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2006&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2006</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>2</ID>
<Title>Guardian</Title>
<ArtistName>Ted Shillock</ArtistName>
<Description>- Titled abstract figure created from three different blocks of white marble on dark gray-black stone.
- &apos;Guardian&apos; is a follow-up piece to a smaller &apos;Guardian of the Horizon&apos;.  It was created from three different blocks of marble, each with different colored veins.  The pieces are held together with epoxy and stainless steel pins.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRLUJpdVpIUWt2WUE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667180555556,45.4239555555556</LatLng>
<Materials>Italian Marble</Materials>
<Challenge>Is this sculpture like a human figure?  What is it wearing?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape – Triangles, squares and rectangles.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture – Seen, but not felt, in the smooth marble.</Elements2>
<Details>The slanted lines of the sculpture suggest a moving figure that appears to be ready to step off its pedestal.</Details>
<Story>This artwork is appropriately placed in front of the library because as Ted Shillock has noted, this figure represents a guardian or protector of knowledge, feelings and ideas.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>396</ID>
<Title>Guardian of the Lake</Title>
<ArtistName>Brian Mock</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.brianmock.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>aluminum - aluminum</Medium>
<Description>&quot;crafted from 100% recycled aluminum&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWkNhN3NVZ1FmWlk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.395853,-122.68849</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lake Oswego Rotary</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.lakeoswegorotary.org/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Recycled aluminum</Materials>
<Challenge>How many different items can you identify?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Texture - Smooth or rough?</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Shape - Different shaped pieces create an overall texture for the viewer’s eye.</Elements2>
<Details>The idea for a sculpture begins with Brian’s structural visualization that allows him to see a three dimensional image in his mind.  He first draws his idea, then makes a two dimensional form.  Then he chooses from his ongoing collection of scrap metal the exact pieces that he believes indicate the anatomy of the dog.  He welds all pieces to the form and finally smooths all of the sharp edges.</Details>
<Story>Brian Mock explains:  “I am intrigued by the challenge of creating an entirely unique piece of art from a random collection of discarded and often commonplace objects, giving these old, ordinary items a new and extraordinary life.”  He wants the viewers to question the reality of what they are seeing.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>436</ID>
<Title>Hobbes Claw - Unsheathed 3</Title>
<ArtistName>Stephen Klema</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.stephenklema.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;The underlying theme in my work is a visual reduction of a complex form into defineable shapes which combined present a coherent figurative form.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNWRnRS1YeUJkdlk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419826,-122.669699</LatLng>
<Materials>Wood, plastic, metal</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you name the famous philosopher whom this sculpture was named after?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Repetition - the repetition of lines and repeated color patterns creates a feeling of movement.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Color - the use of color helps to emphasize shape and form and also allows the artwork to stand out from its surroundings</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - intersecting lines give this sculpture a machine-like feel.</Elements3>
<Details>&quot;Nature&apos;s law of red tooth and claw&quot; is a quote from Alfred Lord Tennyson. Thomas Hobbes believed that all humans in nature are corrupt - hence the relationship to the Tennyson quote and this sculpture (look at the red teeth!).</Details>
<Story>Klema&apos;s outdoor work is fabricated from overlapping and interlocking stained and painted wood elements. The artist is interested in in using wood as a means to explore the transformation and evolution of his artwork through environmental elements over time.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>470</ID>
<Title>Honey + ? 2.4</Title>
<ArtistName>Lin McJunkin</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.mcjunkinglass.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Glass - Metal</Medium>
<Description>Cast glass cells in steel honeycomb suggests bee&apos;s problems worldwide</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTkRnSWE2MzZ0dW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419433,-122.665665</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Beth Schulberg with Cruise &amp; Travel Specialists</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#https://cruztrav.com/about-us/beth-schulberg-owner/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Glass, Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What are the positive benefits honeybees provide?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Value/light - Notice the contrasting values in the individual glass pieces. Some colors are lighter and more translucent than others, suggesting the honey has become &quot;unpure.&quot;</Elements1>
<Elements2>Repetition/Rhythm/Pattern - The repetition of the hexagonal pattern creates the honeycomb.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color - How does color signify the purity of the honey?</Elements3>
<Details>Honeybees worldwide are suffering from a variety of problems that may be related to climate change, including being out of synch with flower maturation. Pesticide use is also an identified cause of Colony Collapse Disorder. This piece warns of those dangers while reminding us in an attractive way of the importance of bees and their honey for our food supply. The powder-coated metal “hive” is filled with fused glass “honey” of varying colors to represent loss of purity.</Details>
<Story>2 years ago, Washington glass artist Lin McJunkin and metal sculptor Milo White began collaborating to transform sheets of steel and glass into a unique hybrid of sculptural elements. White often begins their process with a metal framework that McJunkin fills with fused or cast glass.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016 - 2018 Rotating Exhibition&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016 - 2018 Rotating Exhibition</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>282</ID>
<Title>In the Flow</Title>
<ArtistName>Stuart Jacobson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.stuartjacobsonsculptor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Shorter basalt column</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRckMwOER4RjZ5Umc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.400816,-122.657179</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>178</ID>
<Title>In The Flow</Title>
<ArtistName>Stuart Jacobson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.stuartjacobsonsculptor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Taller Basalt column</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRckMwOER4RjZ5Umc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.657055555556,45.4004138888889</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>399</ID>
<Title>Intention</Title>
<ArtistName>Pasha Stinson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.pashasculptor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Granite - steel</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Is it better to break or bend when faced with the storms of life.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Stinson-Intention.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.669038888889,45.4201972222222</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Dr. Paul Kimbrel, DDS</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.lakeoswegodentalcare.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>South Dakota Mahogany granite</Materials>
<Challenge>This is one solid piece of granite.  How do you think the artist was able to sculpt the arching portion?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Form - Stacked rectangles with curved sides move the viewer’s eye toward the sky creating rhythm through repetition</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Color - Matte earth tones</Elements2>
<Details>This special piece of granite weighing 4,485 pounds was chosen by Pasha and his wife for its warm color and beautiful veining.  Pasha sculpted this granite as it lay in a horizontal position and with his assistant, Levi Hoppes, applied a sealer and polished it to enhance the veining and soft warm glow.</Details>
<Story>“Is it better to break or bend when faced with the storms of life?”  Pasha Stinson wants the viewer to walk around this sculpture and feel a sense of joy on the one side that bends toward the sun; and sorrow or resignation on the other.  The artist’s intention was to create these changing perspectives.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>439</ID>
<Title>Journey Home</Title>
<ArtistName>Angelina (&amp; Joel Heidel) Marino-Heidel</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.artspa.us</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Salmon swim through reeds on their way home to their spawning grounds.&quot;

Sponsored by Dyke Vandenburgh Jewelers</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRVnVPVkxxVXpvNk0</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.417653,-122.663772</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Dyke Vandenburgh Jewelers</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.vandenburghjewelers.com#http://www.vandenburghjewelers.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Powder-coated mild steel and vitreous glass enamel</Materials>
<Challenge>If these fish were indeed &quot;journeying home,&quot; which direction would they be swimming?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - the use of colors enhances the playful quality of this sculpture.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Space - notice how the spatial area of the sculpture has a larger footprint than the actual sculptural elements. With so much negative space, the artists are still able to create a sculpture that is meant to be viewed from all sides.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - the combination of vertical and horizontal lines increase activity for the viewer; your eye is constantly moving left and right as well as up and down; to follow the lines requires active movement.</Elements3>
<Details>This style of work is inspired by the Art Deco and industrial movements in art. The graphic quality of the work as well as the exposed hardware exemplifies this connection.</Details>
<Story>Salmon swim through reeds on their way back home to their spawning grounds. The circular shapes represent water bubbling up as well as roe. The sculpture is anchored to a concrete pad built below the pavers.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>438</ID>
<Title>Klein Suspension</Title>
<ArtistName>Paul West</ArtistName>
<Description>&quot;If a gourd with 1 side and no edges existed in nature, it may look like this, sprouting from the artist&apos;s mind into matter; two dimensions representaed in 3D to conceptualize the 4D!&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRYXpVTnJtUG12d0k</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419848,-122.667281</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Cascade Coil Drapery</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://cascadecoil.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Steel, Bronze, stone, aluminum</Materials>
<Challenge>4 different materials are used to create this sculpture. Can you list the materials and point out where they are on the sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape/Form - the bulbous form of the sculpture creates both positive and negative space.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - although there are many elements that compose this multimedia sculpture, the way the elements are arranged gives a feeling of stability to the whole piece</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture - the numerous components in this sculpture allow a diverse range of textures, from smooth but scaled steel to smooth but unpolished stone and metal.</Elements3>
<Details>The Klein Bottle, which this sculpture was inspired by, has one side and no edges. It is a non-orientable surface which, if traveled upon, could be followed back to the point of origin while flipping the traveler upside down.</Details>
<Story>A Klein Bottle has no example in the natural world; it exists soley in the mind of humans.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>6</ID>
<Title>Leaf Figure</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRMXdPSV96WjNJcW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66356,45.4178</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>211</ID>
<Title>Linear Prism</Title>
<ArtistName>Lawrence Morrell</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.lawrencemorrell.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Glass, color LEDs, reflective panels</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-10/LO-artscouncil-newart-14.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.664286111111,45.4198083333333</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>380</ID>
<Title>Little Boxer</Title>
<ArtistName>JD Perkin</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jdperkin.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;An introspective moment&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Perkin_LittleBoxer.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667555555556,45.4195972222222</LatLng>
<Sponsor>The Caldwell Family with Thanks for Connor</Sponsor>
<Materials>Stoneware</Materials>
<Challenge>Did the boxer win or lose?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color – Earth tones</Elements1>
<Elements2>Form – Repetition of rounded shapes</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture – Surface scratches and lines in the clay</Elements3>
<Details>The artist likes to provide a sense of mystery in his artwork; individual details require careful observation.</Details>
<Story>JD Perkins background in the performing arts is conveyed in the mood, gesture and position of this boxer figure.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>435</ID>
<Title>Lookout</Title>
<ArtistName>Heather Soderberg-Greene</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.heathersoderberg.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Lookout is coyly playful, preening in the sun, showing off his shimmering patina.</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-16/Lookout-ACLO-new-art-16.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420718,-122.66514</LatLng>
<Sponsor>PHK Development Inc.</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.phkinc.com#http://www.phkinc.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Bronze with patina</Materials>
<Challenge>What kind of bird does Lookout represent? Can you find this bird in Lake Oswego?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - Notice the beautiful hues that bring the sculpture to life. The gradient of hues help to enhance the shape and illuminate the beautiful lines of the sculpture.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Value - the lightness of the silver nitrate patina actually allows the bronze to show through. (Note the feather area)</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - The vertical lines of the sculpture draw the viewer&apos;s eye up and down rather than focusing on a specific part of the sculpture.</Elements3>
<Details>Pelican (a poem written by artist Heather Soderberg-Greene): &quot;Had I but wings like thine/To soar between/Those airy deeps and lower deeps more real/Above the wrecks and ruins of the sea/The joy to feel/Of freedom on unfailing pinions mine/Had I but wings like thine/ To visit lands/Of ancient story and shining rennown/To roam and rest beside those glittering strands/That ages crown/With words and thoughts that lustrous gems outshine.&quot;</Details>
<Story>The artist seeks to capture her subject matter using minimal detail. She explores smooth planes and curving angles to create shaped combined with a bright and contemporary silver nitrate patina that is semi-translucent so the bronze can show through.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realism&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realism</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>55</ID>
<Title>Lotus Tower</Title>
<ArtistName>Joel Cottet</ArtistName>
<Description>Lotus Tower is made of several sculptural ceramic pieces anchored together to form a column 14.5 feet high and 5 feet across, and weighing 1500 pounds.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRMlRDQnQ0UmRxTms</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420419,-122.659599</LatLng>
<Materials>Clay</Materials>
<Challenge>Think about each piece of this sculpture being made individually by the artist. How many pieces are stacked to create this tower?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Pattern - find references to the lotus flower.</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Shape - cylindrical and symmetrical</Elements2>
<Details>Glaze:  Blue-green color gives a light and airy feeling to this very tall ceramic work.
Unity: Provided by repeated references to the lotus flower petals and its leaves.</Details>
<Story>The lotus flower is an object of perfect beauty in Chinese mythology. Joel Cottet specialized in large-scale pieces he formed on a potter’s wheel. Lotus Tower was originally a part of Gallery Without Walls in 2002/03 and was purchased by the city of LO from the estate of the artist in 2005 after his death.</Story>
<Style>Representational</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>400</ID>
<Title>Matelasse</Title>
<ArtistName>Reven Swanson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.revenswanson.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>	http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Swanson-Matelasse.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.663472222222,45.4176583333333</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Delap, LLP</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>http://www.delapcpa.com/#http://www.delapcpa.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Powder-coated steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How has the artist made the metal look like fabric?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Color: - Dual-sided light and dark colors make the sculpture eye-catching</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Pattern - Repeated</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Shape: - Spiral, moving the viewer’s eye</Elements3>
<Details>This contemporary sculptor loves fabrics and needle arts.  Matelasse is one of five in the series “Helix Fabric” that depict the transition and evolution from fiber to metal.</Details>
<Story>Imagine you are twirling a long ribbon in a circular motion.  Swanson has taken this idea and created a metal sculpture.  She has cut a circular pattern in a flat sheet of metal; she then pulls the center while anchoring the ends using chains and wedges creating a continuous strip that seemingly twirls.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>392</ID>
<Title>MerKaBa Dura</Title>
<ArtistName>Joe Burleigh</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.corrosionhelp.com/joeburleigh.htm</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>painted steel - painted steel</Medium>
<Description>Mer= Light, Ka= spirit, Ba= Body. Turn on your MER KA BA today</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Burleigh-MerKaBaDura.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667730555556,45.4199138888889</LatLng>
<Materials>Painted steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How does this sculpture move?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Line - Straight and repeated in a geometric shape of a stellated octagon</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Balance - Kinetic interlocked double tetrahedron turning on a central column</Elements2>
<Details>The multi layers of colored enamel will flake off over time unveiling another color underneath; points are purposefully rusted giving the patina of age.</Details>
<Story>In ancient Egypt, these words all had meaning:  Mer – a kind of light that rotated within itself; Ka – spirit; Ba – human body; Dura – solid or hard.  Putting it all together, a rotating light would take the spirit and body from one world into another.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>459</ID>
<Title>Mushroom Drums</Title>
<ArtistName>Yelena Roslaya</ArtistName>
<Description>My coil-built sculptures, inspired by udu drums, are abstractly representing soundwaves, which are often heard and not seen. These drums create low and deep sounds, coming from the shape of the hollow clay form as the resonation bounces against the walls of the clay body. Hands are the best when it comes to interacting with this sculptural instrument.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRa0NyWm1QUW9QdUk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420261,-122.664161</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Kids of Lake Oswego</Sponsor>
<Materials>Ceramic, glaze</Materials>
<Challenge>Which drum makes the loudest noise when &quot;playing&quot; it? Hint: Drum on the holes.</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape - The bulbous shapes of the drums suggest an organic form as illuminated in the title, Mushroom Drums.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Color - The contrasting glazes give singularity to each particular drum.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture - the mixed use of ceramic and glaze, sometimes used unevenly on the surface, helps to add texture to the drums, and provides a variety of surface finishes.</Elements3>
<Details>These drums create low and deep sounds, coming from the shape of the hollow clay form as the resonation bounces against the walls of the clay body. Hands are the best when it comes to interacting with this sculpture instrument. Make sure to drum on the holes on each scultpure, not on the sold surfaces of the drums.</Details>
<Story>&quot;Udu drums, which originate in Nigeria, can be found in many varying shapes and sizes. They are used as pots for storing food, transporting water, and as instruments for ceremonial purposes. These drums do not need skin to make their sound and most of them are completely made out of earthenware clay. Yelena’s coil-built drums tend to be organically shaped, in such forms as gourds, mushrooms, and carnivorous plants. The mushroom-shaped drum has a cap form, which is hollow and creates a resonating sound quality when tapped or touched. Depending on its size, the mush-room cap has a hole or two that produce the deepest sound when drummed upon. The stem of the mushroom-shaped drum gradually curves from the cap into the stem, where it’s thicker to support the weight of the sculpture. This thickness of the mushroom drum allows it to withstand environmental wear-and-tear as well as the drumming interaction.&quot;</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>393</ID>
<Title>Mutatio</Title>
<ArtistName>Ben Dye</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.bendyesculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Stainless steel &amp; basalt - steel plate</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Technology and math play a critical part of each sculpture, it is meant to challenge the mind and the eye.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRby1mRnN1WHVSa3c</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.410131,-122.72014</LatLng>
<Materials>Basalt and stainless steel</Materials>
<Challenge>When you move the rods, how does this change your experience with the art?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Line - Combination of straight and curved, repeated</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Movement - Viewer interacts with the sculpture</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Texture - Cut, ground and honed basalt; smooth rods</Elements3>
<Details>“Mutatio” is the Latin word for change, meaning to move or shift.  It is the viewer who changes the sculpture to create a new profile for the next viewer to enjoy and change.</Details>
<Story>Ben Dye started with a 6000-pound basalt column.  He built a diamond wire saw that he used to cut a ten-inch wide slab from the basalt.  The saw does most of the work; it polishes and created texture as it cut.  He then used a template to drill holes for the rods made of stainless pipe that are held in place by stainless steel bearings.  The completed work weighs 1750 pounds.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>444</ID>
<Title>Origami #3 - Totem</Title>
<ArtistName>Ken Hall</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.solsticestudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;The origami series is an exploration in folded steel.&quot;

Sponsored by Jackie MacGregor</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTEg0T21paUxZSWs</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420116,-122.670271</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Jackie MacGregor</Sponsor>
<Materials>Folded and welded mild steel with powder-coat and natural patina finish</Materials>
<Challenge>How many origami folds does it take to create one flower on this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Value - the density of the blue powder-coat enhances the sculpture&apos;s presence on the street and allows it to stand out against its surroundings.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - the verticality of all of the lines in the sculpture encourages the viewer to continue looking upwards.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Space - the distance between each flower is derived from the Fibonacci sequence.</Elements3>
<Details>The distance between each flower on Origami #3 - Totem is calculated through the Fibonacci sequence. This is nature&apos;s numbering system and the sequence appears in natural phenomena such as the arrangement of plants and patterns in flowers.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture is part of the artist&apos;s series of origami flower sculptures. It is based on Hall&apos;s interest in the Japanese tradition of paper folding as well as his observation of Native American totems which can be found in the Puget Sound area where he is from.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>401</ID>
<Title>Outcropping Anew</Title>
<ArtistName>David Turner</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.rockfarmstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Addressing quandaries of working, resting, reasoning, and the unknown.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>	http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Turner-Outcropping-Anew.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667408,45.418461</LatLng>
<Materials>Reclaimed cedar and found stones</Materials>
<Challenge>How do you interpret the pile of rocks?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Texture - Sanded cedar, natural rock</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Form - Geometric chair juxtaposed with the natural shape of rocks</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Balance - Purposely created with the stacked stones</Elements3>
<Details>Turner sees the potential beauty of stumps, branches and stones that he cleans, cuts and positions into a harmonious whole.</Details>
<Story>These collected objects are laden with meaning and associations.  Turner is inspired to move them in and out of preconceived notions causing the viewer to confront the objects in a new light.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational with an abstract concept&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational with an abstract concept</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>465</ID>
<Title>Pilot (Stars Aligned)</Title>
<ArtistName>Vicki Lynn Wilson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://vickilynnwilson.net</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Mixed Media</Medium>
<Description>A spiritual exploration of learning, growth and flight.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQnZvbnNpWkdud00</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.41997,-122.668076</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Toniya Villalobos in honor of my mother, Iva Znobia</Sponsor>
<Materials>Steel, cement, enamel paint</Materials>
<Challenge>Point out as many recognizeable shapes and images in the upper half (steel) portion of the sculpture. What do you see?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Balance - Notice how the elements are arranged to create a feeling of stability.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Contrast - Notice the juxtaposition of the white, polished cement with the textured and painted steel to help engage the viewer and add to the complexity to the sculpture.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Texture - Notice the diverse textures within this sculpture. The steel parts themselves contain multiple treatments and textures.</Elements3>
<Details>Pilot is from a series called &quot;ERA,&quot; made as a way of celebrating the artist&apos;s 40th birthday, as a rite of passage to recognize who she has become.</Details>
<Story>&quot;The human form has such a narrative capacity, and material holds a symbolic language. Here, the figure is a support, a vehicle, and a culture on which to grow my material experiments. In creating this wrok, I release the past and realize my potential. This has been an era of study which I began as an apprentice and ended as a professor. Much of the work I produced in the twenty years preceding was thoroughly planned from the inception. In this work, in the spirit of letting go, I responded spontaneously to the materials and the forms in each stage of completion.&quot; - Vicki Lynn Wilson</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>39</ID>
<Title>Pinecone Bollards</Title>
<ArtistName>Valerie Otani</ArtistName>
<Description>- Small bronze pine cones on 36&quot; tall poles located in a space next to road.
- The bollards depict the legend that the shape of the pine cones of the Douglas Fir are the
tails of mice, running for shelter from the Oregon rain.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUWdaUXdIOEdrQW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.655019,45.407539</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>437</ID>
<Title>Planta Triformis</Title>
<ArtistName>Sue Friesz</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.suefriesz.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;The transformation of a plant from a drawing in the field to a sculpture through reduction and exaggeration.&quot;

Sponsored by Bill and Barbara Warner</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRRUMyMS11Nl9UTjA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419701,-122.668128</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Bill &amp; Barbara Warner</Sponsor>
<Materials>Coated aluminum</Materials>
<Challenge>What does Planta Triformis translate to?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Space - the metal cut outs in each of the plant forms creates positive and negative space that controls the movement of light through the sculpture.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Repetition/Rhythm/Pattern - the repeated forms with slight derivations as well as the repeated cut-outs with slightly different shapes enhance the whimsical quality of this artwork. It gives the work overall unity but adds a layer of complexity as well.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Value/Light - the variation in value of the colors chosen for each plant creates an effective contrast between different components.</Elements3>
<Details>Planta Triformis is made out of (3) bi-morphic shapes that have differently sized and shaped cut-outs. At different times of day, viewers will notice different shadows cast on the sidewalk and concrete base surrounding the sculpture.</Details>
<Story>Before beginning any sculpture, the artist starts with plant drawings outdoors. Friesz explores the influence of natural vegetation in overlooked settings. Once the drawings are complete, she scans the drawings and highlights the part she uses for each sculpture piece. Once it is fabricated, she then decides on colors.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>133</ID>
<Title>Rams Head Benches</Title>
<ArtistName>Ken Patecky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.patecky.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>1 of 2 pieces.
Two wooden benches with two wooden concrete ram heads, one at each end of the bench.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUzQ0blBySVo0WHM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.717619444444,45.4123694444444</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>408</ID>
<Title>renovation</Title>
<ArtistName>Sharon Warman Agnor</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.sharonagnor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>stainless steel - cast glass</Medium>
<Description>A visceral commentary on conditions required for recovery and repair

Nominated for People&apos;s Choice 2016</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-renovation.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420261,-122.666726</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Beth Levich with Cruise Holidays of Portland</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.cruzholidays.com#http://www.cruzholidays.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel, copper, cast glass, enamel</Materials>
<Challenge>Why do you think there are locked windows over the sculpture&apos;s eyes?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color—enhanced by the juxtaposition of the metal form and the brightly painted elements</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line—curves accentuate the figurative nature of this artwork</Elements2>
<Elements3>Balance—the curved sides flow along a strong central core creating a balance</Elements3>
<Details>The heart element hanging from the sculpture is fabricated from cast glass. Cast glass is the process by which glass objects are cast by adding molten glass into a mold for solidification. This is a process that was used in Ancient Egypt and Rome.</Details>
<Story>Agnor’s work focuses heavily on the unpredictable life events. Her personal experiences have largely influenced her artwork, and sees our ability to sustain loss as amazing and central to our existence as humans. The artist uses materials that are extremely transformed through heat such as steel, bronze and glass. “Beauty, joy, injury and fear seem to power the story of my life. renovation invites commentary on the conditions required for recovery and repair. The view from afar shows a posed figure with eyes closed and shut windows. The story gets refined as one nears the elements within a cast glass center where action is intricate.” -Sharon Agnor</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>397</ID>
<Title>Ringer 7</Title>
<ArtistName>Ulrich Pakker</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.rpart.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>stainless steel, bronze - stainless steel plate</Medium>
<Description>Within Ringer 7, its balance, connection and linkages create a bridge extending from my studio to the site and the viewer.</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Pakker-Ringer-7.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.667302777778,45.4198611111111</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless steel, bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>What’s the largest negative space you can find?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Texture - Smooth or rough?</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Shape - Different shaped pieces create an overall texture for the viewer’s eye.</Elements2>
<Details>These negative spaces act as peepholes.  Look from the inside through the holes, like through a telescope, at the scene framed by the curving shapes.  The artist wanted to create contrast and balance through the use of two metals.</Details>
<Story>Ulrich Pakker describes Ringer 7:  “The most dynamic aspect of this sculpture is the broken ring which has slipped through the piercing to rest against the base.  Even though the ring looks like it might slip out again, it will not.  Just as the ring is permanently part of the sculpture, the parts of a community will always hold it together allowing survival and growth.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>472</ID>
<Title>Royal Blue</Title>
<ArtistName>Heather Soderberg-Greene</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.heathersoderberg.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRN3F6ZVo2dFU3OUk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.42073,-122.665187</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>464</ID>
<Title>Sail</Title>
<ArtistName>Rodger Squirrell</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://metalsquirrell.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Aluminum/stainless steel welded with explosive bonded weldment.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUUw1aE9FNkxBaW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420327,-122.666776</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Eric J Weberg with Edward Jones</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#https://www.edwardjones.com/financial-advisor/index.html?CIRN=409554#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel, aluminum</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you tell what parts of the sail are made from stainless steel and what pieces are made from aluminum?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line -  The gestural curved and straight lines come together to represent the sail form.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Form - A form is a self contained defined area of geometric or organic form. A positive form automatically creates a negative form. Can you point out the positive and negative forms in this sculpture?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Contrast - How does the texture of the sculpture differ from shape to shape?</Elements3>
<Details>Squirrell&apos;s metal sculptures feature a wide range of industrial remnants and sheet goods repurposed as bold, modern forms. He gives cast off materials new life through the mediums of masks, fountains, wall sculptures, and public art installations.</Details>
<Story>&quot;The material drives the idea, so I accumulate scrap materials that sit around the studio in piles. I usually have three or four sculptures going all the time. Eventually they start to work on me and I have to do something with them. Some pieces don’t gel right away and I just let them sit until they do. I’m recycling more than just the physical weight of the metal. I looked at automobile bumpers for a long, long time before I could see something in them. Chrome bumpers are obsolete now, but a lot of design and tooling, and physical energy is still present. I want to capture that energy – not just put it in a scrap bin and melt it away.
It’s showing respect for the process and the people that made the original part. That’s how I feel about all materials. They represent a lot of work already and I’m trying to add something new.&quot; - Rodger Squirrell

Sometimes the life you give a sculpture is not the life you intended. You’re working in a kind of unknown realm. You have to work slowly and hope that something great emerges. You can only predict things to a certain level. That’s the whole mystery. You can start out to make a horse, make a bad horse, and end up making a good dog.&quot; - Rodger Squirrell</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>394</ID>
<Title>Salacia</Title>
<ArtistName>Jen Ellsworth</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.fairyforge.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>steel &amp; plants - steel &amp; rubber</Medium>
<Description>&quot;She is the Roman goddess of spring water, who gently sways in the breeze.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Ellsworth-Salacia.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66974316921333,45.419899066952446</LatLng>
<Materials>Steel, rubber, plants</Materials>
<Challenge>What is the most graceful part of this artwork?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Line - Vertical, curved, repetitive</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Color - Red grounds the piece, green plants complement the red</Elements2>
<Details>This innovative recycled metal sculpture is kinetic and gives new life to scrap metal pieces.  The use of succulents at the base asks the viewer to wonder why they are used.  Jen Ellsworth and her husband began a metal fabrication business in 2006; in their free time they enjoy creating things that don’t require a blue print.</Details>
<Story>Ellsworth sees scrap metal pieces as having the potential to look beautiful and having another life and another story to tell.  She wants to create art that lifts the spirit and expands the mind of the viewer.  She searches heavy machinery auctions, military surplus stores and auto junk yards for these unwanted pieces in their original form.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>391</ID>
<Title>Samaras</Title>
<ArtistName>Matt Babcock</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.mattbabcock.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>powder coated steel - steel</Medium>
<Description>&quot;A samara is a seed with a wing, such as a maple seed&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Babcock-Samaras.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.668202777778,45.419725</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Jackie MacGregor</Sponsor>
<Materials>Powder-coated steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Are the two pieces mirror images of each other?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Line - Rhythm, movement, repetition</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Balance - Equal size and design of the two opposing halves</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Shape - Positive/negative</Elements3>
<Details>This welded metal sculpture is a result of Matt Babcock’s lifelong interest in nature and how things work.  A samara is a seed with a wing such as a maple seed – a whirligig.  Matt purposely chose the tarnished silver color to give a sense of elegance in keeping with the gracefulness of the sculpture.</Details>
<Story>Matt Babcock enjoys the numerous interpretations voiced by others when viewing Samaras, e.g. a butterfly and other insects, or two people facing one another.  His formal training in architecture, engineering, metal fabrication, mathematics and art history are all represented in Samaras.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>426</ID>
<Title>SirenaSerena</Title>
<ArtistName>M.J. Anderson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.mjandersonsculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>A mermaid born of the sea with ancient geologic patterning.</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-sirenaserena.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419520,-122.664529</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Robert and Bonnie Schlieman</Sponsor>
<Materials>Italian marble</Materials>
<Challenge>What do you think caused the geologic patterning in this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape - The form creates an extreme contrast of positive and negative space.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture - Smooth and rough
Shape - The form creates an extreme contrast of positive and negative space.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Unity - Between the artist’s base and sculpture.</Elements3>
<Details>On the backside of SirenaSerena are geologic patterns made by watermarks that reference the long history of this stone and carry this history within its form.</Details>
<Story>SirenaSerena provides the slightly abstracted but still figurative form of a mermaid sitting atop her marble pedestal. Hand carved by the artist with hand-picked stone from a quarry in Carrara, Italy, like many of the artists work, it focuses on the female form and story to explore artifacts from different cultures. With the use of aggressive tool work, the artist creates texture and contrast with a highly polished surface. MJ Anderson hand picks her stones from Carrara, Italy. (This is the same type of marble Michelangelo used to carve David). Anderson’s subject matter explores artifacts from distant cultures. With a strong focus on figurative female imagery, the artist uses these forms to share universal stories of women.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>412</ID>
<Title>Spiral Petite</Title>
<ArtistName>Micajah Bienvenu</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.artmb.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>An uplifting spiral, inspired by math and nature



Nominated for People&apos;s Choice 2016</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-spiral-petite.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419577,-122.667608</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Eric J Weberg, AAMS®, Financial Advisor, Edward Jones</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#https://www.edwardjones.com/en_US/fa/index.html&amp;CIRN=409554#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel</Materials>
<Challenge>How does this sculpture invite public interaction?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - The grinding technique on the stainless steel provides visual texture</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - Although the form is asymmetrical, its upward movement gives it balance</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - The curved and flowing line in this sculpture allows your eye to conceive of this sculpture as a whole</Elements3>
<Details>The artist uses a disk sander to create interweaving marks on the sculpture. This process creates the burnished texture that you see. This creates spatial depth and reflective qualities that allow the artwork to be in a constant state of transformation.</Details>
<Story>This artwork falls into the artist&apos;s series that focuses on spirals that ascend vertically. Bienvenu choses spirals as a subject matter because they reference the relationships between people, the natural world and the community. The artist uses 3-D modeling software to create his artwork. He combines graceful lines with gyrating shapes, and interior mounts oftentimes allow for kinetic movement.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>261</ID>
<Title>Spirit of the Marsh</Title>
<ArtistName>Mark Andrew</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.markandrewstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Stone</Medium>
<Description>50 foot long, multi media sculpture graces one end of the Headlee Walkway in Lake Oswego .  Forty-four tons of rock anchor 29 cast bronze cattails in a naturescape which integrates natural with man-made landscape elements.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWGlGU0FLUTlvd1E</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66383,45.41756</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>214</ID>
<Title>Sprout</Title>
<ArtistName>Mike Suri</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.suriiron.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdnRFeGp5blgyNUU</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6645,45.4173944444444</LatLng>
<Materials>Steel with clear coated paint</Materials>
<Challenge>How would Sprout change if it was raining? Cloudy? Sunny?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color – gives the piece focus.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line – creates balance &amp; rhythm.</Elements2>
<Details>Sand blasted metal.  Water &amp; copper sulfate bring out the reddish coppery oxide we call rust.  Solution is washed off to stop the rusting.  Leaves are sprayed with shades of yellow &amp; orange paint.</Details>
<Story>The artist states, “trees, especially during the fall season, inspire a great sense of awe and thoughtful calm”.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2010&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2010</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>70</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;At First&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>6 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>57</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;Dreams&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>1 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  Unpolished on 5 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.657013888889,45.4211888888889</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>67</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;Oregon is Green&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>3 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 5 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>69</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;Perfect Stone&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>5 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>71</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;River with One Bank&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>7 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>66</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;The River&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>2 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>72</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;The Stream&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>8 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford. - 1 unpolished side of 5 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>68</ID>
<Title>Stafford Column - &quot;You Reading This&quot;</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>4 of 9 tall obelisks with engraved poetry by William Stafford.  1 unpolished side of 4 sides.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWDg4WGZ0OEp6cnM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421182,-122.657045</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>462</ID>
<Title>Stone Bench</Title>
<ArtistName>Lloyd Whannell</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.fineartbuilders.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Function and aesthetics joined together, blending into something more.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRX2REWV9meDF6cHc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419743,-122.666506</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Benoit &amp; Associates</Sponsor>
<Materials>Stone</Materials>
<Challenge>What type of stone is used for the actual bench?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - Notice the texture of the top of the bench: smooth and polished; now move your hand under the bench, and you&apos;ll notice the rough, unpolished stone.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - Even amidst the curvature of the bench, the artist is able to achieve balance with the bench and a feeling of overall unity within the piece.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color - Notice how the green of the stone changes value in certain areas. It is lighter in some parts and darker in others.</Elements3>
<Details>The artist uses serpentine stone (green) for the bench part of the sculpture.</Details>
<Story>The bench is an example of the functional work the artist fabricates, combining function with the ability of the piece to hold its own as an artistic sculpture.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realism&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realism</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>47</ID>
<Title>Sunbathers</Title>
<ArtistName>Ken Patecky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.patecky.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>- A mother holds a child on her lap while looking up into the sky.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRMmtJSElfT095bWM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.666213888889,45.4194833333333</LatLng>
<Materials>Concrete</Materials>
<Challenge>We easily recognize this as a mother and child, but what parts of the figures are not realistic?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Line - horizontal and vertical lines emphasize the closeness of the figures and the body positions.</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Texture smooth.</Elements2>
<Elements3>	Color - This monochromatic sculpture focuses the viewer’s eye on the figures.</Elements3>
<Details>The artist first makes a wooden form, then pours tinted concrete into it.  While the concrete is setting up, he sculpts it with a large flat spatula.</Details>
<Story>Legs are extended and faces are raised as the mother and child bask in the sun’s rays.  This timeless and universal portrayal won the 1st People’s Choice Award in 2001.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2001&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2001</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>402</ID>
<Title>Sunflower</Title>
<ArtistName>Patricia Vader</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.patriciavader.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Stainless steel &amp; Aluminum - Stainless steel</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Like the circles that you find in the windmills of your mind&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRTTM0T2Etd0VwMzg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66489597032972, 45.419495235469725</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Dyke Vandenburgh Jewelers</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>http://www.vandenburghjewelers.com#http://www.vandenburghjewelers.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Stainless steel, aluminum</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you name another artist famous for sunflowers?</Challenge>
<Elements1>	Color - Hues of the sun</Elements1>
<Elements2>	Line - Curved stem and petals</Elements2>
<Details>This kinetic sculpture consists of eight windmills. These windmills are made out of bicycle wheels with canted disks, which represent the heart and seven petals of the flower.  The windmills spin in different directions (clockwise and counterclockwise) depending on the direction of the wind and the orientation of the disks. The heart of the flower has road reflectors mounted on each disk that flare up at night.</Details>
<Story>Born in Amsterdam, Vader earned her PhD in Mathematics and Natural Sciences from the University of Amsterdam. She taught Astronomy at Yale University and was an astronomer at the Space Science Telescope Institute in Maryland before moving west and focusing on art, earning an MFA in California.  “My research and creativity focus on technically challenging projects that use the free energy of wind and sun.  I make art that is fun and exciting and filled with motion and light.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2013-2015 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>383</ID>
<Title>Sunrise in the City</Title>
<ArtistName>Jesse Swickard</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jesseswickard.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;Built to see the sun within the city&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWlJ0Ui1iNXdQb2s</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.407498,-122.675423</LatLng>
<Materials>Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Why is this titled Sunrise in the City?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Form – Contrast between circular and linear</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line – Predominately diagonal</Elements2>
<Details>Jesse Swickard’s training as a metal fabricator and car restorer has influenced his public sculptures.</Details>
<Story>Jesse expresses himself in a visual language.  By using repetitive, rhythmic lines he shows us how he sees the sun rise.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>218</ID>
<Title>Swoop II</Title>
<ArtistName>Devin Laurence Field</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.devinlaurencefield.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Stainless Steel</Medium>
<Description>Stainless steel sculpture.  Terns and other migratory birds swoop and play in the sky over the lake.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRSE9GRnFSdFBRbFE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.664641666667,45.4130111111111</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>466</ID>
<Title>Taos Patriarch</Title>
<ArtistName>Huberto Maestas</ArtistName>
<Description>The best art in the world has a human spirit behind it. It is created from the soul.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdHVTLVhBQnladkk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419572,-122.667585</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Nicoletta&apos;s Table &amp; Marketplace and Shari Newman - Cascade Sotheby&apos;s International Realty</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.nicolettastable.com#http://www.nicolettastable.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>What part of this sculpture looks most realistic?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - Notice how the pronounced lines make this sculpture look more realistic.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture - Is the bronze smooth or rough? Does the texture change in certain areas?</Elements2>
<Elements3>Emphasis - What parts of the Taos Patriarch does the artist emphasize the most? Why do you think he chose to highlight specific parts of the figure?</Elements3>
<Details>The Taos Patriarch represents the Native American elder who used to stand along the portals around the Taos Plaza in New Mexico.</Details>
<Story>Huberto Maestas is a well-known sculptor from San Luis, Colorado. He is best known for religious sculpture and his Stations of the Cross near his home. The Vatican also has a work of Maestas&apos; sculpture in its collection. &quot;As an artist, my artwork is a reflection of the human spirit.  It is in these intangible events that my art takes an intimate look at the moment; the strength of perseverance, power, struggle and dignity in sculptural form. It is in the tradition of the great sculptors of the Rennaisance, that I am drawn to create works of art that inspire our life experiences. The best art in the world has a human spirit behind it, there is a humanity and spirituality that exists in all artwork, whether religious or not, it is created from the soul.&quot; - Huberto Maestas</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realism&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realism</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>463</ID>
<Title>Tempest</Title>
<ArtistName>James Ellingboe</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jamesellingboe.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Form through the repetition and manipulation of a simple shape.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRLXA0UjdwaVhCcE0</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.42008,-122.666522</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Arts Council of Lake Oswego</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.artscouncillo.org#http://www.artscouncillo.org#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>COR-ten steel with weathered patina</Materials>
<Challenge>Who wrote the famous play, The Tempest?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Repetition, rhythm, pattern -  The repeated triangle shapes are welded together to produce a patterned form.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture - Because of the weathered patina on the COR-ten metal, the texture seems rougher. It will continue to transform with the outdoor elements.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - Notice the combination of vertical and horizontal lines keep your eye moving around the piece.</Elements3>
<Details>Because of the COR-ten material with a weathered patina, the surface of the sculpture will continue to transform with the outdoor elements.</Details>
<Story>Ellingboe is an emerging artist, trained as a landscape architect. His sculptural works are often abstract manifestations inspired by math, science and his life experience with the natural world.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>52</ID>
<Title>The Awe and Wonder</Title>
<ArtistName>Lonnie Feather</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.lonniefeather.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>18 window panes are glass of yellow, purple, red, gold, and black pieces including artistic shapes of white flowing lines, green and blue ribbons (river like), brown flower spheres, and white dots in artwork.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRc3k3U0NFaEdCRVk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.663877777778,45.41835</LatLng>
<Materials>Glass</Materials>
<Challenge>Are you looking down into the water or up into the galaxy?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color – subtle hues of purple, green, blue.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Pattern – Grid of the panes creates a balance to the fluid design of the glass pieces.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Line - Curvilinear</Elements3>
<Details>Three sets of three glass panels with organic shapes ask the viewer to examine their individual framed panes.</Details>
<Story>According to Lonnie Feather, the title focuses on the idea of “the essence of our relationship to the universe – the awe and wonder of life.”  
Note:  You can find The Awe and Wonder by standing in the driveway to the parking structure of Lake View Village and looking above the entrance/exit.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>443</ID>
<Title>The Craftsman</Title>
<ArtistName>Jordan Hall</ArtistName>
<Description>&quot;A man&apos;s face is the paper on which his life&apos;s story is written. Every line a word, every wrinkle a phrase, every star a chapter.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRN0lrd2hWR0xRd28</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419896,-122.662981</LatLng>
<Materials>Polychromed cold cast iron</Materials>
<Challenge>Come up with a story about the identity of the Craftsman.</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - the depth of the incised lines to represent wrinkles inherently points to age and experience.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture - notice how the texture enhances the realistic nature of the sculpture.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color - the choice of the blue-ish silver hue for the face seems to make The Craftsman represent an other-worldly figure.</Elements3>
<Details>The sculpture was originally made from polychromed clay; however, in order to withstand the outdoor elements, the artist chose to cast the sculpture in cold cast iron. The pedestal the bust rests upon was made by the artist to best highlight his sculpture.</Details>
<Story>The Craftsman pictures a forest ranger that the artist worked with in Montana. The woodsman was also an artist and maker himself, hence the name, The Craftsman.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realism&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realism</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>157</ID>
<Title>The Flight of Icarus (Icarus Falling)
(Torso)</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRV01idnhCNTFNbmM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.6638222,45.4179306</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>445</ID>
<Title>The Four Seasons Ballroom</Title>
<ArtistName>Merrilee Moore</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.merrileemoore.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>&quot;My ongoing study of how color, form, texture and implied motion can convey emotion and allow me to express my visions.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRVDRJZUc2dUdjX00</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.421148,-122.664145</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless steel and blown glass</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you pair each sculpture with a different season? What colors represent the particular season most clearly?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - the use of colorful glass is perhaps the most important element in the creation of this piece. The color combinations are used to elicit a familiarity and nostalgia with each season that we all can relate to.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Repetition/rhythm/pattern - the repeated yet assymetrical steel cages clearly distinguish one season from the next, while still offering a feeling of unity for the entire piece.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Form/Shape - the negative space created through the placement of the glass balls within the cages allows for shadows to be cast on the retaining wall on which the sculpture is hung. At different times of day, you will notice color in the shadows.</Elements3>
<Details>If blown in a perfect circle, these glass balls are almost impossible to break.</Details>
<Story>Each cage represents a different season. As your eye moves from left to right, you see winter, spring, summer and then fall. If you look at the sculpture from a side angle, you may notice that the steel cages dance away from the wall to create a feeling a movement.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2015-2017 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>5</ID>
<Title>The Goal</Title>
<ArtistName>Lee Hunt</ArtistName>
<Description>3 pieces - one little boy, one young girl, one young boy and one soccer ball in cast bronze.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRMTNXcllOb1RfMGM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.725802777778,45.4248583333333</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>111</ID>
<Title>The Myths of Icarus:  A Father&apos;s Fear</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNjFSOGxrNG5xRjA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66566,45.4179</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>155</ID>
<Title>The Myths of Icarus:  As Deep as Heaven</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdFRZSk91Y3BkYVE</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66564,45.41799</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>154</ID>
<Title>The Myths of Icarus:  Breathe Deeply</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWGdYOHdvY1dsd0E</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66565,45.41796</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>153</ID>
<Title>The Myths of Icarus:  He Had to Turn Away</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZURROU4wcEFOdW8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66565,45.41793</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>46</ID>
<Title>The Three Graces</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Three armless women.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQ19FaWc2T2htQ1U</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.665041666667,45.4177083333333</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>457</ID>
<Title>The Visitor</Title>
<ArtistName>Geemon Xin Meng</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://www.xmsculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Sculpture creates connections between the imagination and the cosmos.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRWl9rUVpQWldlbWM</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.417491,-122.66359</LatLng>
<Sponsor>The Caldwell Family in thanks for Connor, Cameron &amp; Charlie</Sponsor>
<Materials>Fiberglass, concrete</Materials>
<Challenge>What other City has an iconic big blue bear in its public art collection?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Shape - the lack of negative space within the form of this sculpture adds to the exaggerated bulbous-ness.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Color - the bright blue helps the sculpture stand out amidst its landscaped surroundings.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Balance - the pudginess of the bear, especially weighted towards the bottom half in his pose, helps give the sculpture a feeling of balance.</Elements3>
<Details>&quot;I usually focus on the human condition, but sometimes a figure emerges from the clay whose persona is so compelling I almost expect it to speak. So it is with this bear, a visitor with something to say.&quot; - Geemon Xin Meng       If The Visitor could speak, what do you think it would say?</Details>
<Story>&quot;Geemon Xin Meng is the Director of the Vancouver Sculpture Studio. He is an internationally-recognized professional sculptor working within the tradition of classic, figurative sculpture. After having received a rigorous education at the Fine Art &amp; Design Central Academy of Beijing, he immigrated to Canada in 2004. A prolific artist with exceptional technical skill and vision, he focuses on developing a mastery of the medium while imbuing each sculpture with his own personal, contemporary vision. With over 25 years of experience as a sculptor, he has worked in a broad range of media — clay, fiberglass, marble, stainless steel, hammered copper, and bronze — creating both figurative and abstract works. In addition to teaching students at his Vancouver studio, Geemon is an Artist Mentor in the Master of Fine Arts program at Lesley University in Cambridge, MA. Geemon’s work has been shown in solo and group exhibits in Canada, China, the US and the UK.&quot;</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>73</ID>
<Title>The Way It Is</Title>
<ArtistName>Frank Boyden</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.frankboydenstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Tall thin rectangular columns, polished flat stone, rough back with Stafford poetry.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRbGtHMTEzeVFpQ00</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.665316666667,45.4209138888889</LatLng>
<Materials>Basalt</Materials>
<Challenge>Why did the artist use stone as his medium?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - Vertical lines define the shape of this rectangular pillar.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Texture - The back is natural rough basalt; the front is chiseled and polished to a silky finish.</Elements2>
<Details>The poem was laid out on a rubber stencil that was adhered to the stone face; the following words were sandblasted into the polished surface.  Thin white paint was applied to the sandblasted indentations.</Details>
<Story>This sculpted pillar is a tribute to Lake Oswego resident William Stafford (1914-1993), Poet Laureate, who moved to Oregon to teach at Lewis and Clark College and published more than 65 volumes of poetry and prose during his lifetime.</Story>
<Style>Realistic</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>376</ID>
<Title>Tidal Pool</Title>
<ArtistName>Mary Ann Baker</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.maryannbaker.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>painted steel - bronze</Medium>
<Description>&quot;Rough rocks, tumbling waves, playful critters&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRNXFadjlsMHNVTlU</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.419854,-122.65662</LatLng>
<Materials>Painted steel, bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>How many sea creatures can you identify?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color: vivid red, yellow, blue, purple and green contrast bronze and natural rusted steel</Elements1>
<Elements2>Form: curves repeated to mimic the sea’s waves and ripples</Elements2>
<Details>Mary Ann Baker translates her ideas for sculptures into digital models using several computer programs. Following the computer designs, large sheets of steel are shaped, cut, colored and arranged to form her whimsical works of art.</Details>
<Story>Mary Ann Baker’s art frequently abstracts playful forms from nature—such as flowers, birds, and plants. Her used of bright color enlivens her public art sculptures. Recently, she recently moved her studio from California (San Francisco area) to New Mexico. Do you think this will change the subjects in her art?</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>48</ID>
<Title>Time and Space</Title>
<ArtistName>Stuart Jacobson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.stuartjacobsonsculptor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Black and white granite.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRZWFnSFV5NU9iaTQ</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.723127777778,45.4129666666667</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>156</ID>
<Title>Torso (Nike as Victory)</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQ3pwMUFuX0tselk</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66479,45.41795</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>388</ID>
<Title>Totem</Title>
<ArtistName>Travis Pond</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.steelpond.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRaHo0V1FveDlBQjg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.723389, 45.397139</LatLng>
<Materials>Repurposed Steel, Automotive Finish</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you identify the animals represented in this sculpture?  (Wolf, Beaver, Orca, Frog, Raven)</Challenge>
<Elements1>Contrast - colors and shapes</Elements1>
<Elements2>Lines - Curved &amp; vertical</Elements2>
<Details>The artist collects scrap metal and recombines the pieces into new forms.  Several of the objects in this sculpture were donated by the Fire Station and  location students.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture was commissioned by local business leaders in our community and citizens to watch over and protect our children and the firemen who protect us.</Story>
<Style>Representational</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>456</ID>
<Title>Transcendent</Title>
<ArtistName>Brian &quot;Huts&quot; Hutsebout</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://www.hutsebout.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Wood</Medium>
<Description>Boundless energy flowing through nature - a dance-like vitality.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRenhEc0pQd29FYzA</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418229,-122.662952</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Cascade Sotheby&apos;s International Realty</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.cascadesothebysrealty.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Metal, wood, found materials</Materials>
<Challenge>Does this sculpture present recongizeable imagery? If so, what does it make you think of?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line - the verticality of the steel pipes suggests upward movement.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - the way the elements are arranged achieves this element. The steel rods suggest stability and movement simultaneously.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Repetition/ryhthm/pattern - a regular repetition of elements can produce the look and feel of movement.</Elements3>
<Details>The wood at the tops of the rods is cedar. The cedar was deemed &quot;firewood,&quot; but the artist felt it still have more life. Each piece is individually turned by the artist and then given an oiled treatment to give it the warm golden glow.Transcendent will continue to transform within the outdoor elements, emulating the natural process of nature and transformation. Pieces of copper tubing were then applied to the top and bottom of the wooden bulbs. The &quot;stems&quot; are steel rods inserted into steel tubes. The rods have a patina to turn them dark brown where as the tubes are a shinier steel. The artist used several colors and layers of paint to bring color and vibrancy to the sculpture. To fabricate the banding, the artist experimented with nylon to model the steel. He then applied the final steel banding by heating and wrapping it around the steel tubes. Most of the material from the piece came from Metro&apos;s GLEAN* program. Http://recologyportland.com/oregon_art.php</Details>
<Story>&quot;Influenced by the living world, the artist’s goal is to contrast nature’s unequaled advances with the synthetic rapidity of contemporary human mass production. He intends to illuminate organic, temporal processes that are often overlooked and acknowledge the value inherent in nature. Through art, the artist endeavors to maintain an essential quality of craftsmanship to respect the balance humans should have with their surroundings. In order to maintain harmony with my environment, he works primarily with found or discarded objects. Unlike newly made items, every used material has a voice of its own: a history that has been collected through its existence. It is that history that compels him to reconstruct the clutter around us in a new way.&quot; - Brian Hutesbout</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>271</ID>
<Title>Trillium</Title>
<ArtistName>Matt Cartwright</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.cartwrightdesign.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Mixed Media</Medium>
<Description>Powder-coated steel, aluminum and acrylic.  The three leaves at the base of the sculpture are intended as seating.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBReWtwblJ6S21mN0U</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.660072222222,45.410375</LatLng>
<Materials>Powder-coated steel, aluminum with acrylic</Materials>
<Challenge>If the sculpture were painted one color, how would you still recognize the flower?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - separates the elements of the sculpture.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Shape - Triangular shape of a trillium plant&apos;s petals.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Space - Positive/Negative</Elements3>
<Details>Trillium is appropriately sited on the banks of the Willamette River in George Rogers Park.  Go sit on the bench and experience a quiet moment.</Details>
<Story>Trilliums are woodland wildflowers native to the temperate regions of North America that bloom in April and May.  If you pick the flower, the plant will not bloom again the next year.  If you pick the leaves as well, it will not re-grow fro many years.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;People’s Choice Winner 2009&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>People’s Choice Winner 2009</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>420</ID>
<Title>Tsunami Memorial</Title>
<ArtistName>John Zylstra</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.brittonroadstudios.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Mild steel - plexiglass</Medium>
<Description>The Fukushima Reactor is the inspiration: rusted metal &amp; shoji style top.</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-tsunami-memorial.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420072,-122.666514</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Nicoletta&apos;s Table &amp; Marketplace and Berkshire Hathaway Home Services</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.nicolettastable.com#http://www.nicolettastable.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Mild steel, plexiglass</Materials>
<Challenge>Can you guess how tall this sculpture is?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - Marks and wear on the gong will continue to transform to look weathered</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - Draw your attention upwards towards the roof.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Unity - of the entire structure to give a monumental impression.</Elements3>
<Details>The gong form is textured and painted to look as if it is an artifact from the tsunami and reactor. It will continue to transform as it reacts with outdoor elements.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture was inspired by events in Japan and the resulting media images.  The raw steel of the tower and gong forms, combined with roof and partial sides., suggest a kinship with the disable reactor by revealing a rusting and potentially derelict interior. Leaving the marks on the gong form, I intent to reference the remaining scrap and twisted metals from various sites to imply relics and/or objects of memory, not unlike the fascination with elements that remain at the site of the former World Trade Center.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>428</ID>
<Title>Twist</Title>
<ArtistName>James Ellingboe</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.jamesellingboe.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Cor-Ten steel - weathered finish</Medium>
<Description>An abstract manipulation of a simple geometry inspired by diatomic organisms.


Sponsored by Bonnie Cartwright</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-twist.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418303,-122.664631</LatLng>
<Materials>Cor-ten steel with weathered finish</Materials>
<Challenge>Does this sculpture look the same from the front and back?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Space -  The spatial presence of this sculpture encourages the viewer to see it from all sides.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Shape - Positive and negative shapes.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Balance -  The unique shape still provides balance without symmetry.</Elements3>
<Details>The rust color of the sculpture is actually just a patina over the COR-ten steel that will continue to transform.</Details>
<Story>Twist is an abstract form inspired by the study of diatoms. Diatoms are a group of algae and represent a common form of phytoplankton. They oftentimes survive in colonies that take the shape of zigzags, stars, ribbons or FANS! As you can see here, this fabricated diatom, Twist, has taken the form of the fan. Complexity in form, light, and shadow is achieved through the manipulation of basic geometry. The relationship between positive and negative space is in constant flux as you move around the piece.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>468</ID>
<Title>Under the Spell</Title>
<ArtistName>Ross Matteson</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>http://mattesonsculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Wood</Medium>
<Description>A framing tribute to the spellbinding grace of the peregrine falcon!</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRdVdDak9ka0pQT2M</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.41845,-122.667167</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Bonnie Cartwright</Sponsor>
<Materials>Bronze, Steel, Cedar</Materials>
<Challenge>What type of bird is perched on top of the gateway?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - Notice the soft and smooth texture of the bird. The falcon has a cobalt patina which gives it this smooth effect.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - Notice the detail in the carved cedar inserts in the upper portion of the steel cross section. The curved lines provide a more organic element to the black steel.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color - How does the use of black in this piece effect the  atmosphere?</Elements3>
<Details>The words on the top of the artwork read &quot;Under the Spell&quot; in runes, the elfish language from J.R.R. Tolkien novels.</Details>
<Story>This artwork is an actual gateway with a life size bronze of a peregrine falcon resting on top. As a life long falconer and lover of J. R. R. Tolkien&apos;s novels, birds and runes are very likely subjects in Matteson&apos;s sculpture.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realism&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realism</Style2>
<Misc>2016-2018 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>188</ID>
<Title>Untitled</Title>
<ArtistName>Bruce West</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.brucewestsculptures.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRVVYzUDFlRllfWWs</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.7279194,45.4112250</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What words would you use to describe this monumental piece?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Balance – Horizontal and vertical forms create a unified whole.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Pattern – “Quilt like” combinations.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Rhythm – Created by the placement of the forms</Elements3>
<Details>From afar the viewer wonders about the silver reflection of the sculpture; when the viewer nears the work, one sees that the reflection is enhanced by the artist’s burnishing of the stainless steel.</Details>
<Story>Bruce West is a retired professor of art from Lewis and Clark College who has been a part of the GWW for many years.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>411</ID>
<Title>Upstream</Title>
<ArtistName>Mark Andrew</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.markandrewsstudio.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Bronze - Marble</Medium>
<Description>Creating a symbol for what we all can believe in..Salmon Upstream!</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-upstream.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.41954,-122.666566</LatLng>
<Sponsor>KeyBank</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.key.com#http://www.key.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Bronze, marble, steel</Materials>
<Challenge>What type of fish are represented in this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - Juxtaposition of the smooth metals with the rougher travertine marble</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - emphasizes the direction of the fish</Elements2>
<Elements3>Repetition/Rhythm/Pattern - Produces the look and feel of movement</Elements3>
<Details>Upstream celebrates the artist’s handiwork at his preferred artistic process, carving. This piece involves hand carved stone, cut steel and bronze and the combination of the three materials, while stagnant, is able to provide the viewer with a sense of movement and delight.</Details>
<Story>Mark Andrew works mostly in stone, wood and bronze media. His work explores nature and emphasizes carved imagery of flora and fauna, which you can see reference to in this sculpture. Andrew writes, “I fill myself up with the essence of my subject and interpret it sculpturally, following humbly in the footsteps of the past and keeping an ancient art form alive.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>286</ID>
<Title>Vincent</Title>
<ArtistName>Keith Jellum</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.keithjellum.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Cast Bronze sculpture of the hare from Alice in Wonderland.  This is a 4 ft. cast edition of the original 8 ft. work that is located in Pendleton Park in Portland, OR.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRU2ZpN2pYSFh5a0E</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.426133,-122.668042</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Jennings Insurance</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://www.jenningsinsurance.com/index.htm#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Cast Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>Is this a rabbit or a hare?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture – look and feel of fur.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line – straight, vertical, curved.</Elements2>
<Details>Alert, looking at you, ready to move, whimsical</Details>
<Story>You are looking at a hare.  Hares make their nests above ground.  Rabbits nest underground.</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Realistic&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2010-2012 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Realistic</Style2>
<Misc>2010-2012 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>387</ID>
<Title>Walking Warrior</Title>
<ArtistName>Sharon Warman Agnor</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.sharonagnor.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Stainless steel - copper leaf, enamel, fused glass</Medium>
<Description>&quot;A celebration of the cost and courage to fight cancer--a tribute to those brave ones who have gone before me.&quot;</Description>
<ImageLink>http://www.artscouncillo.org/tour/images/Agnor_WalkingWarrior.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.666458333333,45.4197388888889</LatLng>
<Sponsor>In Memory of Melanie Sessions</Sponsor>
<Materials>Stainless Steel, Copper Leaf, Enamel, Fused Glass</Materials>
<Challenge>How does this female figure tell you she  is a survivor?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line – Diagonal creating a striding movement</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - Horizontal stripes</Elements2>
<Details>Find the following colors in the sculpture:  copper, black, silver, pink, red, blue.  Is there a sense of emotion created by the use of color?</Details>
<Story>“The last year and a half for me has been an intense focus to survive Breast Cancer.  The fight for life comes at high cost.  The courage required to face the future and to progress is represented here by an armored forward motion.  Walking Warrior is my story of this bruising transformation and is a celebration of this cost, and this courage, bourn by those brave ones who have gone before me.”  Sharon Warman Agnor</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2012-2014 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>160</ID>
<Title>Wall Fountain 1</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRd3VoV1VBeHlhZU0</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66499,45.41803</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>161</ID>
<Title>Wall Fountain 2</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRUC01YVRwaWtKVms</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66504,45.41803</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>162</ID>
<Title>Wall Fountain 3</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRckRaajg0R2RqdG8</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66531,45.41806</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>163</ID>
<Title>Wall Fountain 4</Title>
<ArtistName>Simon Toparovsky</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.simontoparovsky.com</ArtistWeb>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBROEpVYnNFd2JiWnc</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.66537,45.41807</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>49</ID>
<Title>Water, Water, Water</Title>
<ArtistName>Bruce West</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.brucewestsculptures.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Flat mounted square panel with patterns of waves in steel.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRSGdzV3V2LXY2c1k</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.666722222222,45.4205722222222</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Why do you think this design was chosen for this fire hall location?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line – Can you find a straight line?</Elements1>
<Elements2>Rhythm – Balanced movement is created by the repetition of curved lines and scalloped shapes.</Elements2>
<Details>As an abstract work referencing reality, this sculpture presents a sense of water rushing from seven firemen’s hoses.</Details>
<Story>This work was commissioned by the City of Lake Oswego and added to the new fire hall in 1999.  We are fortunate to have a noted Northwest sculptor in our collection.</Story>
<Style>Abstract</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>417</ID>
<Title>What Does the Nose Know?</Title>
<ArtistName>Ron Simmer</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.artblast.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Metal - Mixed Media</Medium>
<Description>Big Brother knows you better than you know yourself.

Sponsored by Lake Oswego Vision Clinic</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-what-the-nose-knows.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418446,-122.667165</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Lake Oswego Vision Clinic</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>#http://lakeoswegoeyes.pecaa-sites.com/#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Aluminum, steel, resin, polycarbonate lenses</Materials>
<Challenge>What style of art would you categorize this sculpture? (hint: Andy Warhol)</Challenge>
<Elements1>Color - Bright colors makes the artwork pop against the green landscape</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - The symmetry of this artwork creates balance although resting atop a steel pole</Elements2>
<Elements3>Emphasis - Scale of the nose.</Elements3>
<Details>This sculpture is a commentary on the spying of government and corporations on our private lives—our nosy big brother watching us.</Details>
<Story>Simmer, the artist, uses found objects and recycled materials to fabricate artwork that provides a commentary on contemporary society. He attempts to remind the viewer of their childhood by creating large scale toys. His work is meant to invite interaction and inspired by the Pop-Art movement. He strives to  take consumer discarded materials and give it a new life as something unique and spectacular. The artist writes, “I feel it is the job of the artist to present unpleasant truths on such objects as global warming and reflect the horrors that the mass media does not mention.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>278</ID>
<Title>Wormy Apple II</Title>
<ArtistName>Ed Humpherys</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.wallawallafoundry.com/exhibition/humpherys/</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Cast aluminum.  A three-dimensional, compositional representation of a wormy apple.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRQ19FaWc2T2htQ1U</ImageLink>
<LatLng> -122.66401,45.41658</LatLng>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>421</ID>
<Title>Wy&apos;east (Mt. Hood) Glacial</Title>
<ArtistName>Lin McJunkin</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.mcjunkinglass.com</ArtistWeb>
<Medium>Steel - Fused Glass</Medium>
<Description>Global warming rapidly melts Mt. Hood&apos;s glaciers into steely rivers

Sponsored by Century Link</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-wyeast.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.420572,-122.664113</LatLng>
<Sponsor>CenturyLink</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.centurylink.com#http://www.centurylink.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Steel, fused glass</Materials>
<Challenge>What is the name of the tribe that refers to Mt. Hood as Wy&apos;east?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - The grinding technique on the steel creates the texture of water running.</Elements1>
<Elements2>Line - The curved lines suggest the movement of the river while the sharp edges remind the viewer of Mt. Hood.</Elements2>
<Elements3>Color - Juxtaposition of light and dark helps to put emphasis on the glass ice/water elements.</Elements3>
<Details>The center glass squares have bubble shapes embossed into the surface to match the river bubbles hammered into the surround metal sections. The lower glass square is clear, like the river water. This is meant to reference ice chunks melting through forged steel rivers on Mt. Hood.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture functions as a reminder of environmental awareness to passers-by. The artist created this sculpture as a means to explore changing and challenging natural phenomena surrounding the melting of the Mt. Hood Glacier due to global climate change. The artist writes, “When I read that some geo-engineers had proposed covering major glaciers with gigantic sheets of reflective mylar plastic, I immediately envisioned the piece that would become Wy’east (Mt. Hood) Glacial.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Abstract&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Abstract</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>51</ID>
<Title>Zephyr</Title>
<ArtistName>Devin Laurence Field</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.devinlaurencefield.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Tall silver column topped by birds with outstretched wings.</Description>
<ImageLink>https://drive.google.com/uc?view&amp;id=0B0c3mlsbYPBRb3N0Wll4QnRzeTg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>-122.663383333333,45.4182138888889</LatLng>
<Materials>Stainless Steel</Materials>
<Challenge>Why does this sculpture belong near the lake in Lake Oswego?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Line – wavy, defines movement of osprey and indicates the breeze blowing the banners.</Elements1>
<Elements2> </Elements2>
<Elements3> </Elements3>
<Details>This impressive osprey seems to be turning in flight to return to the lake for food.</Details>
<Story>Devin Laurence Field was awarded a commission to create One World One Dream, the sculpture outside the Bird’s Nest stadium in Beijing, China, for the 2008 Olympics.</Story>
<Style>Representational</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
</PhoneData>
<PhoneData>
<ID>416</ID>
<Title>Zip</Title>
<ArtistName>Jason Johnston</ArtistName>
<ArtistWeb>www.johnstonsculpture.com</ArtistWeb>
<Description>Each of us responsible for the unity of all.



Nominated for People&apos;s Choice 2015.</Description>
<ImageLink>http://artscouncillo.org/GWW/new-art-15/aclo-zip.jpg</ImageLink>
<LatLng>45.418833,-122.664466</LatLng>
<Sponsor>Ater Wynne, LLP</Sponsor>
<SponsorLink>www.aterwynne.com#http://www.aterwynne.com#</SponsorLink>
<Materials>Bronze</Materials>
<Challenge>How many people are represented in this sculpture?</Challenge>
<Elements1>Texture - The patina on the bronze creates texture as well as the detail in the muscles</Elements1>
<Elements2>Balance - While asymmetrical, the movement of the figures creates balance</Elements2>
<Elements3>Space - The movement of the figures creates complex positive and negative shapes.</Elements3>
<Details>The artist first draws out his idea, then he starts sculpting. He individual pieces together parts, like muscles, arms and legs so everything represents the natural world. Then he uses a rubber mold, wax work, bronze casting, bronze building, and patina to complete the artwork before mounting to the base.</Details>
<Story>This sculpture comes from the artist’s “Human Ambition” series that focuses on the human condition by “exploring our relationships, challenges, and earthly aspirations.” Zip addresses the human condition and the difficulties as well as the rewards of working together to find a common ground in a community. From a distance, this sculpture will look like a zipper, but when you look more closely, it will show the unity of a community acting as the zipper. “Some of them have come together, others reach and aspire to unite, and a few are apprehensive, keeping them apart. Each individual is essential and responsible for the unity of all.”</Story>
<Style>#&lt;![CDATA[Representational&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit&lt;/b&gt;]]&gt;#</Style>
<Style2>Representational</Style2>
<Misc>2014-2016 Rotating Exhibit</Misc>
</PhoneData>
</dataroot>
