<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataroot><tour><name>New Sculptures</name><ids>414,445,447,441,439,437,446,442,434,436,444,443,440,438,456,457,458,459,460,461,462,463,464,465,466,467,468,469,470,472</ids><desc>Tour our new artwork that was installed August 2015 and August 2016 in our rotating exhibit titled “New Sculptures.”  The sculptures will be in Lake Oswego for two years from the date of installation, and all are for sale. For more information about the sculptures, the program, or the Arts Council of Lake Oswego please visit our website.</desc></tour>
<tour><name>Highlights of the Gallery Without Walls</name><ids>361,60,225,141,4,55,214,286,393,402,396</ids><desc>With thirty rotating works of art in the Gallery Without Walls along with thirty two sculptures in the Permanent collection it is difficult, if not impossible, to choose highlights of the collection. However, there are some that children and adults alike gravitate toward in our downtown core. They are representational and abstract, thought provoking and straight forward, large and small. These are some favorites.</desc></tour>
<tour><name>Abstract</name><ids>361,141,372,383,375,385,384,393,377,278,414,445,447,441,437,444,456,459,462,463,467</ids><desc>Abstract art is often the most difficult art form for people to appreciate because it does not represent recognizable reality. So prepare to tease your eyes with art that uses shapes, colors, forms and textures as its subject matter.</desc></tour>
<tour><name>Animals</name><ids>225,370,396,376,286,51,439,457,472</ids><desc>Animals have been depicted in art since ancient times - as symbols of gods, as beast of burden, and as comforting companions. Whether realistic or abstract, you will recognize all of them; so come and meet our soaring osprey, whimsical hare and playful bears. The animals in our collect are guaranteed to delight children and the young at heart.</desc></tour>
<tour><name>At the Village</name><ids>361,60,52,4,386,385,377,414,439,441,457</ids><desc>Do you only have a few minutes while waiting for a dinner reservation? Take a stroll into Millennium Plaza Park or along 1st Street for some sculptural surprises.</desc></tour>
<tour><name>Along A Avenue</name><ids>3,372,379,59,47,375,381,437,444,438,436,460,461,462,465,466,467,469,470</ids><desc>Sculptors can express themselves in a variety of different artistic styles - abstract, realistic, or representational. Study these sculptures as you stroll along A Avenue and compare the diversity of self-expression.</desc></tour>
<tour><name>Bronze, Steel, Stone &amp; Wood</name><ids>349,55,382,261,402,447,441,439,446,444,440,438,458,461,466,468</ids><desc>The materials sculptors use in their work are as much an expression of the artist as the subjects they choose.</desc></tour>
<tour><name>Permanent Collection</name><ids>54,60,264,52,225,56,3,349,141,50,59,4,5,58,2,178,55,393,39,133,261,214,57,47,402,218,46,48,388,271,188,286,49,73,278,51,396,442,370</ids><desc>Many sculptures in the city's permanent collection are dispersed throughout the city - in parks, in front of public buildings and in areas not easily accessible on a walking tour.  Enjoy discovering these pieces of art and create your own tour.</desc></tour>
</dataroot>